Krish NAik: Hello, everyone. Good morning.
Krish NAik: Please let me know in the chats.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Thanks, Viraj, for the confirmation.
Krish NAik: Alright, so today… We'll be discussing…
Krish NAik: I think in last class already, I have defined the agenda, the same agenda we'll be continuing today. Okay, like, the agenda is same, according to last class, we have completed the project, and today we'll be talking about, a little bit, query transformations.
Krish NAik: I've already shared that particular notebook, because in the next project, we'll be talking about our
Krish NAik: Let me just start, I think, somewhere here.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the one, yes.
Krish NAik: So, you guys, I think everybody has access to the old one, so let me just… Measured ones.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Today's agenda?
Krish NAik: query transformations.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, first of all, we'll be going through the query transformations part. So, multiple type of query transformations. Already, I provided this notebook, I think, last month.
Krish NAik: How many of you have gone through the notebook?
Krish NAik: Because it's pretty much self-explanatory stuff.
Krish NAik: Because it's just a high-level walkthrough that I'll be giving through, because majorly, most of the things are done through prompt.
Krish NAik: Anybody has gone through the notebook, please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Nobody has gone through at all right, fine.
Krish NAik: Then, today, we'll be talking about, finally, we will come to our, corrective rag.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the third one is… Self-reflective Raga.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, these two things we'll be discussing in our next project.
Krish NAik: Because a lot of topics that we have covered, like Heidi, then comes your hybrid RAG implementation, then comes re-ranking, so all those things we will try to include.
Krish NAik: In the Project 3.
Krish NAik: And with that, even we'll be including CRAG and SRAG. Okay, so sometimes self-reflective RAG, you can… they call it self-rag, so they don't majorly use the term reflective. We'll be going through the research papers of, these two rag types.
Krish NAik: Okay, so initially we will start with the query transformations. So people who don't have the access to the
Krish NAik: A repo. Please get the access to the repo?
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the same repo, which we have been using, like, last month.
Krish NAik: Only, I think, CRAG and SelfRag, these two things that I have added.
Krish NAik: Okay, other than that, it's pretty much the same thing. So you guys can do a git pull, otherwise take a clone, whichever is comfortable.
Krish NAik: Okay, once you guys are ready, let me know, then we will start with the…
Krish NAik: transformations with respect to our rack.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can do a pull, because right now, only I've done the commit. My last commit was last month.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… notebook updates, as you can see, the last one was on 17 January. Okay, and today is, like, February 8th.
Krish NAik: So you can do a git pull, there is no issue with your git pull.
Krish NAik: Once everyone is ready, you can let me know.
Krish NAik: The implementations are based majorly on Langchain, so…
Krish NAik: Like, I think in the requirements, I've not checked the requirements now, but yes, land chain, landing, all good.
Krish NAik: Others, please provide a confirmation in the chat.
Krish NAik: Only one person, more mothers done, what about adults?
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. Now, today's session is going to be pretty much easy stuff, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay, so majorly, this part is much easier as compared to, like, project sessions.
Krish NAik: So, pretty much self-explanatory, you can open the notebook directly.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, as, because here, initially, I started with only 3 types of queries. Later on, I have added more. So, first of all, the query rewriting part, it means reformulating queries to be more specific and much more detailed.
Krish NAik: Then you have a step-back prompting technique with respect to queries. Okay, so all these examples, one by one, we'll be going through that.
Krish NAik: So, if you have this, please do have a check that you have, because right now, I'll be working with OpenAIP according to your configuration, use Gemini, Ulama, whatever the thing, please do the configurations. Because here, everything will be based on an LLM call.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please, do that and let me know. Let me check my input section is working fine or not.
Krish NAik: Alright, the imports are working fine, so I think we are good to proceed. So, you guys can provide me the confirmation that you guys have configured your own API keys according to your own LLMs that you are using.
Krish NAik: What is the use of query transformation? Just think about if somebody passes something which doesn't make a lot of meaning, or only just one word or two words. In that case, the idea is you will be reformulating that a bit.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mohit, for example, Mohit, sorry. Abhijit, sorry, maybe, do we need to pull? Yes, do a pull simple. I have just committed, I think, two notebooks that I have added, the CD, that is correct.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: You will understand that when we look into the examples, Moe. You can directly look into every each and output.
Krish NAik: It means that from the client side, you cannot expect that every user
Krish NAik: Will pass a good… you probably might be missing some words.
Krish NAik: Okay, probably missing some type of grammatical meanings. In that case, a query rewriting step is important.
Krish NAik: And so many techniques are there, so we'll be discussing few of them.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once you guys have configured your LLM, please do let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just check, for example, the first one, you can just execute the first cell for a confirmation, so here, like, I will just run the first one, okay?
Krish NAik: Okay, and for example, this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just check you are getting the output from the LLM, it's fine, then we can start our discussion. Taking a poll already.
Krish NAik: It's 9.20, so… just… because today we have enough time.
Krish NAik: We have limited topics.
Krish NAik: Once done, okay, a few people are ready, few people are not, please.
Krish NAik: You can use the same environment.
Krish NAik: Also, like, which you were using in the last class for this particular report.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there is no issue with that.
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me start the… D&D.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: So, let's start. So, first of all, now, here, in this particular notebook of query transformations, I have kept multiple approaches. So, the first one is, like, query rewriting. Okay, many people call it, like, reformulating also. The main purpose is to make changes in this query.
Krish NAik: If you are missing some type of words, missing some type of grammatical meaning.
Krish NAik: Okay, using an LLM, you will try to do a reframe on top of that.
Krish NAik: Then you have your step-back prompting, subquery decomposition. So, step-by-step, let's explore, because it's better, rather than going through the theory. Let's try to understand it by looking into proper examples.
Krish NAik: So, the first one is a query rewriting, okay? So, here I have a chat prompt template. Okay, so I've given the name query rewrite template here. So here's… okay, I think the font is visible for everyone.
Krish NAik: So, simply, I'm telling that, okay, you are an AI assistant tasked with reformulating user queries to improve retrieval in your ad system.
Krish NAik: Given the original query, rewrite it to be more specific, detailed, and likely to retrieve relevant information.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, this is the original query which will be passed by the user, which is basically your input variable right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that, the incoming query Okay, now…
Krish NAik: I'm defining my prompt template according to LanChain, so here I'm working totally with LanChain. The same thing can be done in Llama also.
Krish NAik: So, I'm passing the input variable, which is, right now, this particular placeholder that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then, the template definition.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, a simple chain. Okay, so a simple LLM chain. First of all, here I am passing the query rewrite prompt, and then the rewrite LLM. Okay, so two things that comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: Now, a simple invoke operation, and based on that, I'll be getting the response. So, this is a simple function, actually. It was the…
Krish NAik: Yeah, I hope you get, like, just for one line, I've added a function, though the function was not necessary.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me just, try to execute this. Okay.
Krish NAik: And now, for this particular…
Krish NAik: document as we were working with that climate change document, so based on that, I have passed my original query, like, what are the impacts of climate change on the environment?
Krish NAik: I'm calling my function rewriteQuery. So this is the function, actually, that I'm calling, which will actually go through the main prompt, and it will make the LLM call.
Krish NAik: To make your query much better, okay? So, let's just execute this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right here, this was the original query, okay? And, like, how does the climate change affect various aspects of the environment, such as
Krish NAik: Biodiversity, ecosystem, weather patterns, and sea levels.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, there is no document context.
Krish NAik: Okay, so without the document context, it's trying to generate it.
Krish NAik: Now, I can say that, generally,
Krish NAik: Most of the times, this LLM call, that we are making it
Krish NAik: to… and because this is an open LLM, open means not open source, I am making a call to an LLM. But actually, like most organizations, what they do, they will be creating an SLM, because the LLM should know about your data, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: That is the main purpose. If the LLM knows about your data, it can reframe the question better. Because right now, this is pretty much generic task.
Krish NAik: But simply, if you have an SLM, the same thing that can be done, because the SLM will be trained on top of your own data.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for enterprises, it's better to always go ahead with a custom LLM, so that's why I told an SLM for this particular purpose.
Krish NAik: Alright, now,
Krish NAik: Alright, let me just go through the chats. Mahmat is asking, it feels to me that this will work very well with Heidi. It works for all, but, first somehow felt more about Heidi. Yes, Heidi is also good. Heidi is just, like, I feel, always a good approach to do that.
Krish NAik: Then, Mantaj is asking, we are generating or refining the query.
Krish NAik: You can say that it's not refining. Rather than reformulating is the main word.
Krish NAik: Because, yes, for sure, we are generating using an LLM, but it's not refining.
Krish NAik: Okay, refining, generally, when we say the term, so somehow we make it shorter on touch.
Krish NAik: Okay? So don't use the term refining, rather than use the term reformulating in that way.
Krish NAik: Now, Poonamara Nanda is asking, can't we use the RAG approach here? This is the first step to the RAG.
Krish NAik: It means that this query will go to your rack.
Krish NAik: Punam.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, for your RAG approach, then what do you want to do? Do you want to check your, all of your retrieved chunks, and based on that, do you want to formulate that question?
Krish NAik: Yes, this is a cost increase for ship.
Krish NAik: Query transformations, yes, you are making an LLM call, so cost increase will come.
Krish NAik: Okay, gonna, I mean, provide embedding instead of creating an LLM.
Krish NAik: You want to provide an embedding.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, just think about, the user asked a query. Alright, you converted that query into embedding. What is the next step that you are planning?
Krish NAik: Just think about, if the portion is somehow not meaningful, do you think that anything will work.
Krish NAik: Because once you have the query, I can say that you can pass it to the retrieval. But think about the user I've just written, like, tell me the impacts.
Krish NAik: then it becomes much harder, because right now, I have written it in that way, just if it's much shorter query, then the idea is to reformulate.
Krish NAik: pre-embeddings.
Krish NAik: Okay? The cosine will… the cosine will be cosine. Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mohammad, you were telling, we can calculate the pre-embeddings. Now, once you have done the embedding, I can say embedding. So, pre-embeddings, what is that step that you are referring? Whoever, like, in the chat.
Krish NAik: Because here, I always prefer, rather than making an open call to any LLM, it should be based on your SLM, or anything like that. It's always a better approach, at least.
Krish NAik: And it's not necessary to create a smaller version of, I can say any decoder based off that you can pick up, or a sequence-to-sequence model close to 700MB. That also you can join it on top of your custom data.
Krish NAik: anything like big assets that you can pick up, you can pick up T5, all those models are really good. It's not necessary to really pick up something big. Big is not required in this particular case.
Krish NAik: I need to, reformulate, then the embedding. Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: That is the same thing. It means we are reformulating the query, and then the embedding will be created.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pretty much self-explanatory stuff here.
Krish NAik: Now, R is asking, we are doing this step to improve the retrieval DS. That is the idea.
Krish NAik: Now, in today's discussion, it's all about improving the retrieval. Whenever we are talking about query transformations, what is the main priority? Improve the retrieval.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, like, once we start with CRAG, then I will say that if the retrieval doesn't work, simply make a fallback to web search.
Krish NAik: Deepak is asking, how does the LLM know exactly to do? Like, in this case, to reformulate the query? So I have passed it through the prompt, no?
Krish NAik: But the LLM doesn't know about your data, that's why I told.
Krish NAik: that using an SLM is much better here.
Krish NAik: At least a nano version of GPT also, that within 8 hours, you can train it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so according to your docs, that can also be done.
Krish NAik: Some version of GPT is always good, because in this case, really, like, right now, my priority is not making an SLM, but you have to understand, in enterprises, that's how they go ahead.
Krish NAik: Because within 8 hours, you can easily stack. You need to spend close to $250 for that particular, trading approach, but yes, it can be done.
Krish NAik: Now, Imran is asking, if we pass the query correctly, then again, on top of it, no, you will take a condition when you feel that, that doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can pass some type of conditions, where you feel that only, based on the number of characters also, it can be… it can be based on number of words, somebody has written only 2 words, or 3 words. So, based on those particular logics, you can apply. It's not necessary that every time you apply query transformation.
Krish NAik: Probably some user has already, used some type of chat GPT or Claude, okay, and they have reformulated that.
Krish NAik: So that can also… it's not a necessary step. Now, these are the totally optional things that I'm teaching.
Krish NAik: Like, I always don't use query transformations. I use some type of logic that, okay, it can be based on characters, it can be grammatical, like, through a simple spaCy, model also, I can detect that particular thing.
Krish NAik: It can be, because at least the… if I'm working with English language, the idea is that grammatically, it should be at least correct.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. No.
Krish NAik: Now, Mitesh… okay, no, no. Those are, architectural level differences, Mithesh, that you were asking.
Krish NAik: Now, Charan is asking, at which case we have to do a query rewriting. When you feel that, to… your retrieval quality is low.
Krish NAik: Sure. Then, the first thing is the query transformation.
Krish NAik: Because there are so many things in the rack, now I can say that, okay, work on your partsie, work on your chunky, those things are fine. But right now, very specifically, I'm talking about only the query part.
Krish NAik: Because here, everything is good. Just think about if somebody has passed a bad query, what work? The only thing that you can do is a transformation step.
Krish NAik: I hope, Sharon, you get that. Raul is asking, query translation.
Krish NAik: So it's embedding lines up better? Yes, that's the idea, like, if you will be having… and generally, what happens when you are actually working with contextual retrieval? Okay, like, in every chunk, I keep a particular question also.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, that approach, I'm not taught you, but I'm telling you about that. Okay, so in every chunk, you also keep a caution, like, question with your actual chunk information.
Krish NAik: In that way, like, with respect to that question.
Krish NAik: I can say the retrieval works better.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's another way. So, Raul, you were correct with that. Now, is this statement correct? Yes, the statement is correct. See, the main thing is here, reformulate the query. The idea is that it will generate better embeddings.
Krish NAik: See, whenever I say that it will generate better quality embeddings, it means that, for sure, both the query, the bad query and the good query, both will have the same dimension.
Krish NAik: But the semantic meaning, if I really say with respect to that. Okay, so that should be good.
Krish NAik: Yes, it will be a little bit time-taking process, so for these type of things, use some type of nano versions, mini versions, don't use something a big one, with thinking mode enabled. That is not required here. Use a simple one.
Krish NAik: Okay
Krish NAik: Now, Dig Vishar is telling, how does the fallback work, and how to implement? Simply, like, it… based on the response quality, you will do the implementation. If you feel the retrieval quality is low, in that case, you can do that, Digwisher.
Krish NAik: We need not to transform each and every query. Yes, each and every query is not required, so I told you, you know, this is an optional step.
Krish NAik: It's totally accordingly. If you want to keep this thing, then according to some type of, like, a custom logic, if you feel that. So, I told you, it can be multiple conditions on multiple situations.
Krish NAik: Alright, Rahul, based on the question, I would like to do a routing. It goes to a relation TV, or a vector database, or a graph, and then can be deployed. Alright, so many things we were doing, it means that another level
Krish NAik: Okay, these things you can do. See, at the end of the day, it, now the question comes.
Krish NAik: How much latency?
Krish NAik: If you want something to be fast, or if you want something to be slow. If you… if your priority is something, like, in your use case, you want results.
Krish NAik: like, in very high speeds. Then, generally, I remove these things, because these things will take time. And again, the things that you were saying around, like, okay, you will go to relational DB, or a vector, or a graph.
Krish NAik: Workout Probably infuse, all those things.
Krish NAik: Now, if you are much more focused only on the accuracy, it's fine, then you can use everything.
Krish NAik: It totally depends upon that, according to your use case, whether you can go with higher milliseconds response or not.
Krish NAik: That's the main thing.
Krish NAik: Do we have taken the account of any evaluation metrics? No, nothing with respect to evaluation.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, let's move ahead. I've taken a lot of questions. Okay, now this is the first one.
Krish NAik: Now, there is another, query transformation referred to as a step-back prompting, generating broader queries.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, step-back prompting.
Krish NAik: Majorly, if you look into all those types, it will feel like they does the same stuff, because any type of task with respect to query transformation is to make your retrieval process much better. It only changes with respect to the prompt.
Krish NAik: So here, the step-back prompting. So here, the idea is to make your query much more broader and much more detailed, okay? The last time in the prompt, I have not written that, but this time, very specifically, I have mentioned that.
Krish NAik: So, an assistant tasked with generating broader, more general queries to improve the context retrieval in a RAC system. Given the original query, generate a step-back query that is more general and can help. Okay, now here you can see only these changes are with respect to the prompts.
Krish NAik: So, like, most of the times, I feel that the first one, it works really good.
Krish NAik: But, again, the LLM should have that particular information.
Krish NAik: Okay, so similarly here also, you know that whatever the query that I'll be passing based on that.
Krish NAik: I will be getting some results. So right now, what are the impacts? The idea is to make it much more generalized, so I feel that they have added the term, what are the general effects of climate change on the environment, so this environment has been changed to natural systems and ecosystems.
Krish NAik: Really, like, environment is a natural system, if you really think about. So, very small wedding. So, really, I feel that this is much more with the paraphrasing perspective which has been taken.
Krish NAik: So this entire query transformation is always about prompts, Rishi. So you guys really need to work on the prompts part.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, this decomposition, this is somewhat different as compared to the other two techniques.
Krish NAik: But through a simple ellipse. The idea is, that's why, like, query transformation is not such a important topic that I feel. Because according to your use case, you can always use, because it's a direct use of LL. There is nothing going inside.
Krish NAik: Now, for this query decomposition, I've kept some examples. When you keep some examples in your prompt. What do you call that?
Krish NAik: What do you call that?
Krish NAik: A few short… Okay, one shot we don't call it are… okay, we call it few short.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right here, I have just basked a single example, and I have given… so, you are an AI assistant tasked with breaking down complex queries into simpler subqueries for a RAT system. Given the original query, decompose it into two to four simpler subqueries.
Krish NAik: And that, when answered together, would provide a comprehensive response to the original way. Okay? So, whatever the question, so this is a simple example. You can keep more golden examples. The idea is to, according to your data, you can provide more and more, and based on that, the LLM will respond.
Krish NAik: Now, the sub-query decomposition drop that I have defined
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm passing it through the prompt template, then comes my input variable. Now, this part is exactly the same, there is nothing to talk about here, because the syntax is with respect to land chain, then you have a decomposer chain, and then finally a simple function.
Krish NAik: Now, here, simply, like, a scraping operation with… based on the response. Okay, and right now, this is the response type. So that's why, on top of that, I have applied a script operation, just to get exactly the questions.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just pass it.
Krish NAik: Now, here you have to understand, when you have multiple queries, how to handle your RAG system.
Krish NAik: Because you have, right now, multiple queries, so do you think that
Krish NAik: like, this entire thing, if it goes in one shot. So, for example, that I have done. So, if you try to make… so, right now, I have total 4 questions. Out of these 4 questions, let's take that I'm taking only the top 3 questions, and one by one, I am passing it to my retriever.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, can I say that there will be… so, for example, you have taken top case equal to 3. In that case, what will happen?
Krish NAik: Can I say that you'll be having total 9 chunks?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Okay, 12 chunks is fine if you are passing all the four questions, but I thought about taking 3. Generally, like, all is not required, but you have to understand, whenever the chunks, based on that, so if your chunk size is high, okay, it means your top case size
Krish NAik: then always remember that, based on your chunk size, you need to maintain your context window also, so don't make it very, very long. So generally, top 5 is good for most of the query decomposition step, but it depends upon the query length also. If somebody has passed a query based on 1,000 characters.
Krish NAik: Then, for sure, the subquery decomposition, it will be much longer.
Krish NAik: Okay, and sometimes we try to, like, reformulate in such a way, we add a priority. It means that, it can be a dependency-based, query also. It means that a lot of things are there. It means that the first part needs to be executed, then only you can move to
Krish NAik: Part 2. Okay, and then part two needs to be executed, then only part three.
Krish NAik: Okay, in that way, also, you can do reformulation.
Krish NAik: No, no. Right now, I'm not talking with respect to reenactly. But, always remember, if you're actually going with this particular approach.
Krish NAik: the response time of the rag will increase. This you have to understand. So, whenever you are adding, because these are added operations on top of your rag to make
Krish NAik: the retrieval quality better, but this comes with a cost. On cost, it can be with respect to time or with respect to revenue, both the things.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, like, also, whenever you're performing this, it should not be… so this should be optional modules. When you feel that it is required, then only pick up.
Krish NAik: Generally, for two conditions, always pick up these things. One is if the query is very, very short. If somebody has written only inside 10 characters, and if somebody has written more than 200 characters, or 250 characters, simply try to use these type of query transformation, because in between, everything works really good.
Krish NAik: And going forward, like, again, these things also you need to catch it.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling you, these things also you need to catch it.
Krish NAik: I hope you get the meaning of catch-up, because this is the first level of query.
Krish NAik: So if you actually do a catching, it's really a good thing. Then again and again, you do need to make an LLM call. I hope you get that, and I'm making sense.
Krish NAik: Okay? Yes, Raul, the decomposition part is in it.
Krish NAik: Please repeat once again the catcher part.
Krish NAik: Catching means, say, if I'm making multiple LLM calls, the idea is that to save it in some type of Redis.
Krish NAik: Okay, and really, the query embedding.
Krish NAik: Embedding directly, you can keep the… that, query also.
Krish NAik: Query embedding is much more required if you're working with semantic-based cache, in that case, but you can save that, because I feel that embedding, whenever you try to save embedding in Redis, the size increases. So in that case here, you can directly keep the query else.
Krish NAik: Okay, but again, if you think about, if you want to do the embedding, because that is the next step. Okay, so two levels of quail saving that you have to do in Catching. That is a two-way approach. This is the transformations for that.
Krish NAik: One, and then… because embedding also you can save, but right now, are we calculating the embedding? That is the first thing. Like, once this query transformations with multiple questions, so for each of these questions, they will be adding the embedding. So, if you want to save that, then for your later purpose, even you don't need to spend the money
Krish NAik: Okay, on those embeddings also. So that is the added benefit, if you are actually saving the embeddings.
Krish NAik: So, that's why, like, this totally depends upon your architectural and system design stuff.
Krish NAik: Catching subquery will not make sense.
Krish NAik: Generally, like,
Krish NAik: It's not required, but you can save it, because later on, again, with respect to… because if you're doing the calculation once, then it's better to save it, Abhishek, I will say. Always save the embeddings also.
Krish NAik: But, the size of the redis increases, so always think from that, that after… that when you, again, you will be clearing the cache, okay, so, like, somehow that you need to maintain the redis size.
Krish NAik: Yes, just to be sure, it's not about saving anything in Redis.
Krish NAik: It only… the important things, only we save it. Otherwise, we'll be using some other type of database.
Krish NAik: What if the same query comes, and the catcher will eat? Then it's fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, but just think about, Abhishe, the same query if somebody just misses the single word, if somebody removes the also.
Krish NAik: Okay, then it will not hit your gacha, that part, okay? So, that's why. Now, Sy is asking, can we control on a number of sub-queries? Yes, you can, see, generally the control is bad, Sai.
Krish NAik: If I say that, if you have a big query, okay, of 3 to 4 lines, and later on you told that I need only 4 subqueries, so don't do like that.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can make an open end, and you can leave it to the end, according to its understanding. Don't make the rule pretty much heart-based.
Krish NAik: Now, if you feel that, that, actually 10 questions will be generated, but again, on top of those 10 questions, you try to combine them into only 4 questions, like with AND, AND, AND, that's a bad approach, okay? So don't take that approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, because even in my case, I have mentioned 224, so you can always keep this. But minimum use, I will say, like, 2, okay, and the max value that you can go ahead with
Krish NAik: like, 6 or 8. Don't go more than that. Because then your retrieval, you have to understand more the questions, higher the retrieval time. So don't make your retrieval process, like, very, very slow also.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Hold on.
Krish NAik: Then comes, okay, again, the rewriting, refinement, reformulation, same stuff, okay? So here you can see query expansion. Now, this is where that I prefer much more using the term.
Krish NAik: And then decomposition, simplification, refreezing, okay, restating the question, then multi-query generation. So all these things, I've kept it. Step at prompting, run. Right now, we looked, hide is the document embeddings, this we have already told. Then comes query compression.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes your contextual query enhancement, query translation.
Krish NAik: Let's look into each of these things. So, let me just load the stuff up.
Krish NAik: Initially, I only planned to show you 3 types of transformation, but later on, I have added more and more examples, because these are pretty much prompt-based stuff, so anybody can do it. So, when I say multi-query generation, what do I mean by that?
Krish NAik: Multi-query, meaning?
Krish NAik: Can I say more subqueries in simple terms?
Krish NAik: People are telling, but subqueries are different. Subqueries stuff, think about.
Krish NAik: The same query getting reformulated.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you look here, you are an AI assistant helping to improve search queries, generate number of queries, different version of the following question. It means that
Krish NAik: 3 rephrased version or two rephrased version. I hope everybody understands the rephrasing or paraphrasing.
Krish NAik: It means the same question, but, with the same context meaning, but with different words. You can actually
Krish NAik: check some, like, some type of change with respect to synonyms and others. Same question in different ways, exactly. That is the main objective.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then you can do it. So each version asks the same thing, but with a different perspective, use different word and phrasing, that's why I mentioned.
Krish NAik: Help retrieving relevant information from a vector database, okay, and then the original query. So here, I'm looking into JSON-based responses, so return only a JSON array of number of queries, alternative questions, nothing else. Example format, question 1, question 2, question 3.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me just do this. And right now, directly, you can see, I'm not using any, LangChain part, this is pretty much direct chat completion create, a direct OpenAI call.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because, really, just for this purpose, it doesn't make a lot of meaning to use language. Rather than using the core LLM package, it's much better.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here I'm asking what are the benefits of using RAG in LLM applications?
Krish NAik: Now, what are the benefits? Benefits have been changed to advantages. What advantages does employing RAG provide in LLM applications? How is applying RAG useful in LLM? So, like, the same thing, what positive outcomes can be expected from integrating RAG into LLM applications?
Krish NAik: I hope you get the initial meaning.
Krish NAik: In high level, if you think about it, actually, we are doing the same stuff. It only…
Krish NAik: Based on the prompts.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Pretty much self-explanatory stuff, nothing so much.
Krish NAik: Yes, we can do that, Raul. Like, if you want to integrate Landsmith, save it.
Krish NAik: Because, again, the same query, if I'm doing a rerouting, then only, like,
Krish NAik: It's fine now, you can do that, I have no issues in that. For your initial testing, you can do. Is there any standard checklist present to decide,
Krish NAik: between land chain, no land chain-based implementation. It totally depends upon the developers. I don't…
Krish NAik: prefer using Langshan, neither Lava and Lex.
Krish NAik: And because I've shown you an example, Pure Project. If you don't need YUME, those packages are very heavy.
Krish NAik: So I don't prefer using such heavier packages.
Krish NAik: For every task, there is a specific package. Always try to use them.
Krish NAik: If you need a particular functionality from Lansion which you feel that… which is directly not available, it means that you have to write a lot of code. In that case, you can use Lanshan or Llama. Otherwise, what's the purpose? For beginners, for learners, it's fine. But later on, make it much more smoother, which is…
Krish NAik: Because you know exactly what is your requirement. So why move into a bigger ecosystem when your requirement is just more?
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Now, query rerouting.
Krish NAik: Dimensional designs. Dimensional, like, which dimensions?
Krish NAik: Are you talking about dimensional designs in glass?
Krish NAik: Like, dimensions, you were talking about what dimension?
Krish NAik: Are you talking about embedding dimensions?
Krish NAik: Because this is… that is where mean dimensional designs that comes.
Krish NAik: Okay? Alright, now, the next one, let's look. So, this is the query routing technique. So, purpose, route the queries to the most appropriate data sources. Now, this is somewhere I feel that… this is helpful. Okay, now…
Krish NAik: So, in this particular function, what I have taken, the actual query that is coming, and the available sources. So, tell me where your sources will be available.
Krish NAik: Where your actual sources will be available.
Krish NAik: In your VDB, okay?
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, generally, inside VDB, it will be actually in the metadata, yes, correct biology. Because in VectorDB, we will actually have the embedding, but
Krish NAik: For everything I told you, it's better to save that entire chunk text also inside the metadata. Okay, through that, actually, you can go through and access all of them.
Krish NAik: So here, I'm passing the list of sources, the source, name, description for iSource. Okay, and then, simply, I'm telling that you are a query router. Given a user question and available data sources, select the most appropriate sources to your
Krish NAik: Answering question. Now the question comes here, just think about if you have 1 million sources.
Krish NAik: Then what will happen?
Krish NAik: If you have 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 5, but if you have something like 1,000, 2,000, 10,000 sources.
Krish NAik: Then, do you think that this approach is good?
Krish NAik: Okay, then it's not feasible, actually. Okay, so that's why I'm telling, like, these are all optional stuff, so totally depends upon your own system, things that you can actually do. Now, see, here I'm passing name, description, name, description, now name, description.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I will tell a little bit about intent-based, routing.
Krish NAik: So, generally, what happens, you can create a knowledge base of heroes. This knowledge base is nothing related to your own data.
Krish NAik: It means that you actually look for an intent, okay, according to your query. And then, that knowledge base can be your actual sources.
Krish NAik: It can be some type of JSON-based knowledge source somewhere.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is, like, intent fallback, I'll be showing you examples, but if you can't delete it, it means that it will be probably some type of CSV file, GS1 file.
Krish NAik: Okay, but again, the size of those files cannot be very large.
Krish NAik: It's simple routing mechanism techniques. Because here, the main problem is the available sources. It cannot be very, very long. And also, you need to respect the context window of any LLM that you are using. It's not like that in the context where you can throw anything.
Krish NAik: Generally, domain-specific, I cannot say, okay, if your LLM is generic, and it doesn't have any domain-specific information, then in that case, it's really not helpful.
Krish NAik: But if your LLM is capable of having the domain-specific information, then you have to think always in that. If you ask something the LLM doesn't lose, it doesn't make sense of doing a query routing part.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, that's why in this particular sources, I have taken some ML documents, deployment guides. Okay, now, see.
Krish NAik: Just think about what type of use case when you look here.
Krish NAik: When you look into the sources.
Krish NAik: So, when I say ML DOMs.
Krish NAik: when I say deployment guide, when I say API references and case studies, just think about if they are somehow metadata.
Krish NAik: In your charm, can you optimize your search, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Think in that particular prospect.
Krish NAik: Because, yeah, the main purpose is making your retrieval
Krish NAik: better, faster, so that's why I'm telling. Because I feel that, like, intent-based, that is the main purpose. It means the purpose of that query form there, actually, what is the intent? So based on that intent, you make your search much more optimized.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, that's why that name, ML docs, description, like, machine learning tutor. So, if you have this in your metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay, very specifically a tag like ML underscore docs, then obviously the retrieval will be much more faster. So somehow, we are making… so when you actually do this task.
Krish NAik: of, like, adding in one more LLM call. But in the second step, you are… can actually do an optimization on top of the metadata.
Krish NAik: To think, like, somewhere…
Krish NAik: For sure, it will… it can take more added time, but on top of that, also.
Krish NAik: So, like, through this, and you can actually, like, I feel that this is a good approach for direct metadata selection, or sometimes, even if you want to select collection, if you have a multi-tenant where you have multiple collections. Now, out of that, in which collection it should go in the first step?
Krish NAik: It means that you need to decide that
Krish NAik: A lot of things that can be done based on these data sources, that's why I'm telling. For example, implementing… now, based on collection selection, then comes your RBAC,
Krish NAik: Automacy?
Krish NAik: Role-based access control, those things you can control, yes or no.
Krish NAik: So, always think, doesn't… don't think just about query part. Always think from the bigger perspective, also.
Krish NAik: Because based on this logic, like, close to 60% the logic will be same. And then comes my RBAC logic, according to the access rules that I'll be providing for a certain user.
Krish NAik: Because it's very, very important in a ride system to actually, track that, too. Who is looking for what?
Krish NAik: This is actually a security thing, everybody want to do the implementation. Which user has asked which question and what answer he got?
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, so I feel that this is a powerful technique. Now, the question comes how you do the utilization.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes, query compression. Okay, so now directly… now, see, here what I have taken, I have taken a conversational history, so what is the purpose of using this?
Krish NAik: Tell me. Just think from chat perspective, that's why I've taken that conversational history.
Krish NAik: Because this is something, like, everybody needs to do an implementation when you are doing an user profiling thing. For every user. For past interactions or any conversations he or she has done with the system. You'll be getting the query and the response.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, generally, like, you can do the compression of both the things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so query as well as the response, or only with respect to the queries, that also that can be done?
Krish NAik: Okay, so your entire conversation is… in that way, aliens also understand.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, this query completion, so the actual query that comes into the system.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then your actual conversation history, which is a list of strings here.
Krish NAik: Now, initially, so this is my main context, if you look into. If conversational history is available. Now, this is a certain condition that I put. If there is no history only, then there is no purpose of adding everything in one place.
Krish NAik: Now, finally, in the prompt, if you check URL query.
Krish NAik: optimization expert, compress the following query into a concise search query, okay? So, here, rules remove filler words.
Krish NAik: Then comes unnecessary context, keep only the poor semantic concepts, maintain the search intent. Output should be, like, 3 to 8 words maximum. So here, according to your logic, you can increase these numbers.
Krish NAik: Focus on keywords that would match relevant documents, return only the compressed query, nothing else.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, based on that. Now, this, I feel that when you are doing user level, then it is important. For global level, it is not required.
Krish NAik: This information, where you can actually save it, all this.
Krish NAik: For every user, if you're all, like, if you're planning to use a user-level catcher.
Krish NAik: Catcher can be on user level also, because right now, in our previous project, it was global level. But if it is a user-level catcher, for every user, you are actually maintaining the catcher from the catcher, you can actually pick up directly, and you can do that.
Krish NAik: User level, session level, current.
Krish NAik: Yes, generally, what happens, like, any, like, cloud or chat GPT, whenever you start a session, automatically, all those things come into the context.
Krish NAik: But I cannot say anything like a past interaction that you have done 4 months back. So keep something much more recent.
Krish NAik: That is always a good practice. So, probably you can pick up the past 3 to 4 sessions.
Krish NAik: Okay, of that particular user.
Krish NAik: Because if you pick up something from very old, it doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the main query, okay? So, right now, if you look into… I was wondering if you could help me understand what the main advantages are of implementing a RAC system compared to just a standard language model.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is a verbose query. Let's try to go and see.
Krish NAik: Okay, so 182 characters, the accomplished query advantages of RAG versus SLM.
Krish NAik: Standard language model, it's not small. But this was the actual green thing ES1.
Krish NAik: Because the other things are real, it doesn't matter. I was wondering if you could…
Krish NAik: Really, these things doesn't matter.
Krish NAik: Because they doesn't play such crucial role in building up your
Krish NAik: Contextualized vectors. This will create better context vectors.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that. Okay, so again, based on… whenever somebody's passing a BigQuery, I can say that you can actually check this part.
Krish NAik: Because making the comparison is also important.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I've not taken a lot, but I hope you played this part.
Krish NAik: suggest any session where email deployments…
Krish NAik: Sunnyva's one-do and one-to-one connect. Already I told Rocky a male, I will do that, because machine learning stuff I'm not discussing right now.
Krish NAik: So, during this compression, do we miss any particular keywords? So, actually, here I've told focus on the major keywords that would match relevant documents, keep core semantic concepts, all those things. So, that's why it removed, and focused on the main one. The idea is how you can make your prompt gonna be bigger and bigger.
Krish NAik: Sometimes the prompts are very, very big, and generally we maintain a separate file, prompts.py.
Krish NAik: Actually, if you are working with enterprise-level applications there, we have a very separate folder prompts. Inside that folder, you will be having specific prompt-level files.
Krish NAik: Dude.
Krish NAik: So, yes, it can't be bigger.
Krish NAik: Do we need to maintain separate keywords for project-specific to make sure the LLM doesn't remove? Yes, that will be a good practice.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, compression with, user history. So, here, test with… so here I'm passing, tell me about rack systems. Content rack systems combined with, retrieval with generation. So, two levels. Now, here, the next query that I'm asking, what about the implementation details?
Krish NAik: Okay, now let's see how it does, because previously only one, I can say.
Krish NAik: query, but right now, two things that are coming. The old user and assistant. User means, actually, the user has the query. Assistant means the response of the earlier.
Krish NAik: Now, what about the implementation details? Can you see that automatically it picked up RAG
Krish NAik: To, in this particular query, I didn't pass RAD.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: So, it's always a good practice to look into your conversational history, and based on that, fetch the necessary context if it is not different.
Krish NAik: No, there is no… you can play with this, temperature part, because here, getting deterministic result is not my priority side.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's… but keep it lower, don't keep it very creative also, like, 0.7 or 0. Keep always 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, this is always greater.
Krish NAik: Now, Rahul is telling assistance has the rack. Did it pull…
Krish NAik: And just remove this, and then try.
Krish NAik: If you feel that this is a system.
Krish NAik: And because here, you'd need to really play with… generate full rag from there.
Krish NAik: Okay, Robert.
Krish NAik: Well, I thought.
Krish NAik: This is another one. So, user level and session level, always, with respect to your main systems, you can do that.
Krish NAik: So, here, then, let's talk about, contextual query announcement.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, when I say about query arrangement, what is the meaning of that?
Krish NAik: So, if you really look into the example, purpose enriching the queries with user context and conversational history.
Krish NAik: Okay, now if you really…
Krish NAik: think about. Now, can I say that this was also one type of query announcement, according to our previous example that we have seen?
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Rahul, you were telling remove RAT from here, in both the cases, then how it will understand about RAT?
Krish NAik: There has to be somewhere in the previous conversation, the thing that you are telling…
Krish NAik: It doesn't, because right now it doesn't have any context only about Ryan.
Krish NAik: Then how you can expect the answer that in that particular context you will be having read?
Krish NAik: It is not possible only.
Krish NAik: You feed your input.
Krish NAik: If you have nothing,
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now you can see directly it's talking about system implementation details.
Krish NAik: Because that particular keyword phraser, simply without drag, it won't work.
Krish NAik: Then, probably, if you have… you are adding more history, because I have taken only one right now, if you… from your past interactions, if it can pick up right, then only.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, according to your contextual query announcement, again, I will say this is also around the same thing. Okay, so from, it means that reformulating your query or enhancing your query based on your previous conversations.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why you have that, main query, the actual query which is used, then you have your user context, and then you have the conversational history.
Krish NAik: So here, in the prompt, we are mentioning you are enhancing a search query with contextual information, user context, that, context text, then I'm passing the recent conversation, the history text here.
Krish NAik: And simply, I'm telling you, task announce this query by adding relevant context from the user profile, incorporating conversational history, if relevant, making implicit information explicit, keep it natural, and search-friendly. Return only the announced query, nothing else.
Krish NAik: So, here we are limiting it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now…
Krish NAik: So here, what are the best practices? So, I'm not given best practices about what. Then comes the user context, roles, senior data engineer, experience, focus area, current stack. Then, based on my conversation history, user content, tell me about deploying ML models.
Krish NAik: Assisted content, there are several approaches to, model deployment.
Krish NAik: Let's look into how your final query looks like.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this, what are the best practices, has been reformed to.
Krish NAik: What are the best practices for a senior data engineer with 5 years' experience focusing on MLOps and ML deployment using Python, Docker, and Kubernetes?
Krish NAik: Now, all these things, based on the KBS user context, we are adding them.
Krish NAik: This can be modified to project-specific context, correct?
Krish NAik: But be sure that you have something in the context.
Krish NAik: If, in the context I have nothing, my role is blank, experience is blank, focus area is blank, nothing I have, do you think that it will… it can create some type of enhanced query?
Krish NAik: That particular condition also we have to think about.
Krish NAik: Okay, because here, like, the… because when you are doing a context compression, you have to always understand, remove unnecessary words, and keep it much more clean, and focus on much more important keywords.
Krish NAik: Like, you can remove all those things, it really doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: Now, Aruna, rather than hard coding, can we… see, this is not hard coding, like, this particular thing, it can be much more bigger also. Right now, this is the example of the user context that we have defined.
Krish NAik: In real time, this will be dynamic.
Krish NAik: It means that, in some cases, probably the user has interacted with the system, and he or she might have passed this particular information. From that also, or otherwise, if… just forget about the user context, just think about from the conversational history.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I'm maintaining this user profile. Can I say this user context is much more of a user profile?
Krish NAik: Because this is user-level information.
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: So, whenever you are working even with ChatGPT Cloud, they contain a proper user profile. It means that only user-level information. What this guy has been doing, what type of questions.
Krish NAik: Okay, so they try to create profiles of actual users.
Krish NAik: This is user profiling.
Krish NAik: And you saved that profile in a different place.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Now, Sy, where they store it, can you access it? You can't.
Krish NAik: Generally, everyone who is creating such base products User profiles, everybody is spectating.
Krish NAik: Because at the end of the day, it's important to understand the patterns in their customers. Okay, any type of question. So that's why. Like, conversation is a different thing, but a user context, when I say it's actually a user profiling thing that I'm asking.
Krish NAik: Alright, then, much more personalization from different users right now.
Krish NAik: Try different user context and see how the query matches. Okay, so this time, respect to multiple providers, because if somebody's asking, sometimes with respect to a simple data science, machine learning, engineer, resource side test, so multiple things that I have taken.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, here the response won't be so much good, you have to understand, like, multi… try with different user profiles, when I say. Now…
Krish NAik: The question comes, generally, I don't prefer creating multiple user profiles.
Krish NAik: Because then, my actual user, I feel that, okay, somehow.
Krish NAik: The quality of response decreases with time, but it can be a very specific requirement for somebody.
Krish NAik: So… Just think… I am a data science guy.
Krish NAik: Okay, my entire profile has been built on data science, and if I bring some other profile up from another customer.
Krish NAik: Does it make sense a lot?
Krish NAik: Okay, I don't feel it doesn't make sense, but if somebody has such an use case.
Krish NAik: In that case, it pays much more, because in some systems I've seen, they create 3 to 4 different profiles for a single user.
Krish NAik: In that case, it can be helpful, but really, creating multiple profiles is not necessary, because with respect to time, you need to remove the old profiles, and you need to focus only on the recent profiles much more.
Krish NAik: Then, another. Totally depends upon what type of system that you were designing.
Krish NAik: Now, based on different, profile rules, so, like, the query was, how do I optimize model performance? Now, from data science perspective, how do I optimize deep learning model performance?
Krish NAik: With 2 years of data science experience.
Krish NAik: Then comes ML Engineer. What are the best practices of optimizing machine learning model experience in production with 7 years of experience? Again, the same thing, it's actually fetching up from your previous context.
Krish NAik: Research scientists, what are the best practices for optimizing performance of NLP models in research bead? Because here, the focus area is NLP research, so that's been directly picked up from there.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: So, this is another way. So, generally, in one shot, nobody does this task, because you don't want to perform a task on top of multiple providers, but if you have a requirement.
Krish NAik: Then you can do this type of task.
Krish NAik: Now, little bit, let's talk about… Query translation.
Krish NAik: Natural language to filters.
Krish NAik: Okay, because still now, whatever the things that we're doing, can we say that it's pretty much about indirect prompting?
Krish NAik: How many of you feel that?
Krish NAik: Because I feel more than 60% of the game is directly handled by the LN.
Krish NAik: 40% things that I'm adding from my site, and probably with respect to context and other things, the implementation level is very less, like, less than 10-15% that you are actually doing.
Krish NAik: Majorly, the things are from… LLM site. How many of you agree on this part?
Krish NAik: if you… now… so that's why, generally, based on your data, that's why I told you it's a good practice to have your own SLS.
Krish NAik: A small language model is really good in this, because for everything, making an LLM call doesn't make sense. On top of your data is much better, it could be a much cheaper solution.
Krish NAik: Prompting is mean.
Krish NAik: Naga is saying, I don't agree. Then what do you agree, Naga?
Krish NAik: Preetam, where, can we store it? You can select based on whichever database you want.
Krish NAik: Like, do you want it to be long-term, short-term?
Krish NAik: Generally, for long-term, you can use SQLite-based databases.
Krish NAik: Generally, for, response models, like, you can pick up Redis also.
Krish NAik: No, SLMs will create less latencies as compared to LLMs. SLMs are much faster as compared to LLMs.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, I mean, it's difficult to manage.
Krish NAik: SLMs in large enterprises. If you don't have that, generally, then it's fine.
Krish NAik: But SLMs actually, for longer prospect, it makes…
Krish NAik: Your solution much more cheaper, that's what.
Krish NAik: Abhishek, what we need to train? Okay. If training is a problem, if you feel really, like, then fine, skip that.
Krish NAik: Then forget about it.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Because majorly, I feel that for you guys, training is a pain point.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: It doesn't matter, enterprise, with most available for large life science.
Krish NAik: So, right now, it doesn't matter about the entire, whenever you are building a rag system, I cannot say that one single one.
Krish NAik: SLMs… that's why then I'm going to much more complex architectures. SLMs can be based only on collection level also. A lot of things that comes, but leave it for now.
Krish NAik: Because training looks a problem for most of people. That's why.
Krish NAik: I have seen systems where people use only SLM just for a single collection.
Krish NAik: And then they have 20, 30 different SLMs.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's move.
Krish NAik: lived at Abhishek, because I feel that majorly, like, SLM training, I feel that you guys have worked less on training, rather than consumption more.
Krish NAik: Thank you.
Krish NAik: Later on, then, probably, I'll be focusing much more on training.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's look into other examples. Now, query translation, this I feel this is really important. Natural language to filters, okay? Extracting semantic query and metadata filters from natural language.
Krish NAik: How many of you feel that, from query, somehow, if you can make a relationship with your metadata filters?
Krish NAik: Because semantic search, for sure, on top of VectorDB, you perform a semantic search, but with precise filtering.
Krish NAik: Yes, text-to-SQL will also be useful for this.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. Now, the easiest way you can, perform, but, see.
Krish NAik: Here, def, query translation, two filters. So, query str, available filters, date STR list. Okay, now this is the return type of this particular function, so finally it will be based on a dictionary output. So, filter descriptions, so here.
Krish NAik: Right now, I passed for field values in available filters.
Krish NAik: Now, so this available filters… so from where this particular information of available filters will be coming?
Krish NAik: tell me, from where this available filters got items that I'm doing right now.
Krish NAik: This information will come in your implementation.
Krish NAik: Conversational history.
Krish NAik: No. Not from conversational history. It will come from the metadata.
Krish NAik: metadata of your vector DB.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because I'm… I want to perform a… that's why I've written here, precise filtering means metadata filtering only I'm talking about. So here, I'm, writing the prompt, you are a query translator, extract the semantic query and the metadata filters from a natural language query. So, available metadata filters.
Krish NAik: a filter description that I'll be passing. Then comes your natural language query, the original query which is passed by the user. Parse this into a semantic search query.
Krish NAik: the conceptual question. Okay, so this part, you can keep it as
Krish NAik: Remove the semantic part if you really feel, just focus on the main concept, the conceptual question. And then comes the metadata filters. Specific attributes to filter on.
Krish NAik: and return this JSON in a particular JSON format. From where, later on, you can fetch out the field, and you can apply it on top of your VDB.
Krish NAik: Okay, that is the main purpose here.
Krish NAik: But, like, that's why I told generally in your metadata, you can keep close to 20 to 25 attributes. More the attributes, better the reach. Like, you can pass 20 keys, 30 keys. That's not a big amount of information that you are actually dumping to the link.
Krish NAik: So the LLM can understand that.
Krish NAik: before the call to the vector DB, from there you can actually do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now I'm, let me just take a simple example. See, here I'm telling you this is my query.
Krish NAik: If I say that these are the available list of filters.
Krish NAik: Here, list here. Topic, here. Citation. Now…
Krish NAik: I can say, now, the question comes, when you are defining your metadata filters, before that, you have to decide, like, how many categories, what are the different types.
Krish NAik: Okay, so those things you can actually pass it. And it's not about using all of your filters. There will be certain filters, I can say that few of the filters, there the categories will be 10,000, 20,000.
Krish NAik: Okay, but…
Krish NAik: This is not about using tools. Rather than pick up those where you have fewer categories where the classification can be done much more easier.
Krish NAik: Okay, so based on that, you can always pick up.
Krish NAik: So here, now these filters, and try to use those filters according to your vector, like, vector DB metadata design. This is very important. If the design is different, and you are passing some different filters, it doesn't make any meaning.
Krish NAik: Alright, so here, the query, show me research papers about the transformers published after 2020 with high citations, okay? Now, here, again, a list of values, topic against some values, so key value pairs that you have.
Krish NAik: And, author, so print the natural query, the available filters that I have.
Krish NAik: Right now, as you can see, this is a simple JSON dump, which is an actual dig that I have.
Krish NAik: On top of that, I will be performing the query translation. So, simply, I'm calling our main model. Look at the query translation to filters.
Krish NAik: Now… From here, you can see, so this is the list of available
Krish NAik: Filters. So, from here, the final translation result, research paper about transformers, and these are the filter category. Now, from here, if you can extract, so something like here, after 2020, citation count is high.
Krish NAik: Now, these values can really play a crucial role in making your search much more optimized, because every
Krish NAik: VectorTV supports metadata filtering. There is not a single Vector TV in market who doesn't support this type of operations.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I feel that, this approach is implemented in more than 60-70% of the RAT systems.
Krish NAik: Anybody who's building a microSAS also on top of a RAD product, everybody's using this.
Krish NAik: Because from the user query, how you can extract the filters, that is the first level, the fastest way of doing anything.
Krish NAik: And this is really important in…
Krish NAik: enterprises, because in your case, you just need to pick up the categories which will actually help you to make your search much more optimized.
Krish NAik: Because that's why I'm telling you, if your metadata is much more vibrant, Then you get better results.
Krish NAik: Oh, is this a type of self-query as well? Yes, a self-query, because right now.
Krish NAik: This query, though it's using an LLM, so directly self term, I don't want to use, but if you really think in that perspective, it's type of self.
Krish NAik: Because actually, you are trying to look within your system, that's why.
Krish NAik: Haris is asking, we are working exactly on the same risk case on query writing and metadata filtering on our team. Share documents, yes. Based on the documents, you need to do. So that's why the metadata design is really important.
Krish NAik: Because, like, you can update the metadata design also, but again, that's a tedious task. It means that you would be updating any, vectors, the original embeddings. Only the metadata for every chunk that you can actually do an update.
Krish NAik: So, initially, that's why I always say that according to your use case, create a good, rich, and vibrant metadata.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, another simple example of, similarly translating. So, again, here I have multiple filters.
Krish NAik: Okay, now these filters actually help you. So, this is a simple e-commerce filters category, price range, brand, rating, and stock that I have taken. Now, the e-commerce query, find me, highly related, Apple laptops under $1,000 that are in stock.
Krish NAik: Okay, so query translations, let me look into the filters based on this.
Krish NAik: Find Apple laptops filters rating, okay, 4 to 5, because 5 is the maximum one.
Krish NAik: Price range, 100 to 500 and over 500, yes, these two conditions are satisfied, because under 1,000, yes, this is correct, brand apple and stock, yes.
Krish NAik: So, how many of you feel that this is a good approach? Because really, I feel that more than 60-70% of the RAC systems are using this.
Krish NAik: If you're actually building an enterprise level, you should actually work on this.
Krish NAik: VectorDB, and, this one.
Krish NAik: It's really helpful, because at the end of the day, you don't need to look into your entire vector DB. For every call, it's a very bad practice to look into all of your chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, alright, I think I've kept it some… because I've discussed a lot of approaches. Not every approach is available in LandChain, but, a few things are available, like single selector, multi-selector. Okay, these implementations are there that I think.
Krish NAik: So you can check out, like, land chain patterns.
Krish NAik: Pretty much a self-query implementation in Lansion that you have.
Krish NAik: Then, lava index patterns that you have, okay, the multi-step, sub-question, query decomposition, they implement very similar logic behind the scenes. Your routing logic, your routing query engines, so all these engines are available, but again, I have shown all custom implementations.
Krish NAik: Because according to your things, you should change this.
Krish NAik: SAN no is filter automatically added to the user, input? No, no, no, no, no.
Krish NAik: That is the output from where you actually try to find out the filters.
Krish NAik: It is nothing related to the input. It's the output.
Krish NAik: That you are doing.
Krish NAik: Nitesh is asking,
Krish NAik: Alright, so if you really look… under… Under, okay.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, here, the standard implementation will not be changed, the prompt, right? Yes.
Krish NAik: You cannot change the prompt directly if you start using… you can change the prompt, but you have to look into the actual landshell implementation from there. So Mahmat is telling Paul the filter under underscore 1000 was not in the filter. Yes, underscore 1000 was not there, so it translated.
Krish NAik: Because this is a query translation that has been converted into under 500 and 100, because both of these conditions satisfies that.
Krish NAik: Even you can keep under 50 holes.
Krish NAik: Because here, all the logic that we have written, it's for under 1000 only.
Krish NAik: So, the process is, first, we extract the filter metadata, and then get the chance exactly current addition.
Krish NAik: Because there's a much more optimized level of search that I feel that you guys can always work with.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, that's why, like, there are so many things in query transformations.
Krish NAik: But really, I want to say, other things are others, really. Those things I don't give such a priority. But for this query translation, and from that getting metadata filters is a very high priority thing.
Krish NAik: It improves your retrieval speeds.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I really… the speed of the retrieval really matters to us.
Krish NAik: These extracted filters will be passed as a part of the query, yes. Part of the query means when you are making that, vector TB, when you will be invoking your vector TV in that particular condition. So those filters that we can, like, dynamically attach it.
Krish NAik: From the response, directly.
Krish NAik: So that is the added benefit.
Krish NAik: Alright, I provided, like, multiple examples that show up query transformations.
Krish NAik: Initially, I kept thought about adding only 3 things.
Krish NAik: like, rewriting, because even I feel it's pretty much from the LLM side, but I brought much more from…
Krish NAik: Entire system context. User profiling, okay, context completion.
Krish NAik: Not context compression, it's pretty much query compression. Context compilation I'll be talking about later on.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think I've discussed a lot, we can go for a break, then we can start with our C rag and SRAG. Yes, please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, that is for SQL. Right now, I'm not talking with respect to SQL, but even for SQL,
Krish NAik: Like, you can fetch out the filters.
Krish NAik: Sarah was telling this… rough reasoning, okay? This is the paper. It says, high-quality Text to SQL data scale.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: They have their own dataset. If they have their own dataset, yes.
Krish NAik: COT has been applied.
Krish NAik: Chain of thoughts, complexity, query generation.
Krish NAik: Hmm, again, custom model they have used.
Krish NAik: An SLM. This is where an SLM
Krish NAik: Saurabh, that you have… I've not gone through, but I can see directly, these guys are using a syllabs.
Krish NAik: That's why I told SLMs are actually widely used.
Krish NAik: But again, like, later on it.
Krish NAik: Majorly, European clients, US clients, they use SLMs a lot, because the response time of SLMs are very, very low. It's not like it takes 3 seconds, 4 seconds, 5 seconds.
Krish NAik: It can be under 1 second also. It depends upon how we perform those quantization things and others.
Krish NAik: Right now, it doesn't make sense here. It's not from a RAC perspective.
Krish NAik: The prospect is different.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's go for a breath of 10 minutes, okay?
Krish NAik: Can SLMs be productionized?
Krish NAik: People have been using SLM starting from 2018, Muddhasar.
Krish NAik: They didn't use the term SLM, they used the term language model.
Krish NAik: Later on, the categorization has been done. LLF is something more than 8 billion or 13 billion.
Krish NAik: Less than that.
Krish NAik: So, the entire journey of a natural language processing NLP started with SLMs only. They used to call them simple language models. Later on, the parameters increased, and they're tooled at large language models.
Krish NAik: That's the only thing. So if I say BERT, GPT-1, GPT2, what are those? Those are SLF, so…
Krish NAik: It's not like that SLM is totally different. People have been using SLM, but they don't use the term.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Let's start the timer, and then we'll be back in.
Krish NAik: Raja, no, no. Agents, but don't ask me, like, I think, Mank has created one video, you can look into that cloud bot.
Krish NAik: I think he shared the video link yesterday in the group.
Krish NAik: No, no, no UDMA couples.
Krish NAik: You weren't late.
Krish NAik: Right now, everybody is working on that, project part, so nobody is working on Udemy courses.
Krish NAik: others.
Krish NAik: I have no idea.
Krish NAik: But I know that, it's in my calendar, I have to check my calendar.
Krish NAik: I think you'll be getting the mails, no?
Krish NAik: In the mails, I think you get it.
Krish NAik: Nothing with respect to LLM7.
Krish NAik: Here, we don't talk about SLM is so much.
Krish NAik: Probably in the next cohort, I'll be including SLMs.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that a lot of you are having a fear with SLMs.
Krish NAik: Because so many people directly said, no, no, no, no SLMs, that's why.
Krish NAik: If anybody has been working with NLP for, like, 4 or 5 years.
Krish NAik: Everybody has been working with language models.
Krish NAik: No, no, I am not engaging in it.
Krish NAik: Right now, there is no Agentic Bootcamp, coming moment. I think it will be the generative AI bootcamp that Sunny will be taking.
Krish NAik: After that, agentic bootcamp will come after your records is completed.
Krish NAik: That bug will tick.
Krish NAik: Shiva is asking, which I sell as, liquid AI?
Krish NAik: move here just to integrate with LLM.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, there is no integration. LLM separate, SLM separate, sign.
Krish NAik: Both the things are different.
Krish NAik: It's not like you do the integration of LLM, you don't mix LLM with SLM. Both the models are separate.
Krish NAik: Just, your calls are separate.
Krish NAik: Yes, Mama, that is generative AI.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: Dines Singh asking which SLM is good. You can pick up anything from the sequence to Sequence family.
Krish NAik: You can pick up T5… Those things are really good.
Krish NAik: T5 is really good. You can use Bart also from Facebook.
Krish NAik: The main is… the main family that I'm telling is the sequence-to-sequence family.
Krish NAik: We will use SLM for our next one? No, no, I won't be using SLMs.
Krish NAik: The idea is that SLMs have the knowledge about your own data environment.
Krish NAik: When you have your own data, your own enterprise data, then it's a good practice. I hope you get that in that.
Krish NAik: Yes, GraphNag, I will come, no.
Krish NAik: Today, no project. Today, simple discussion. Next week, we will start with the project.
Krish NAik: Lamini, yes, Lamini is good.
Krish NAik: Anirot.
Krish NAik: I've used Lamin in production.
Krish NAik: Lamini is an underrated model, meaning people don't know about Lamini. Okay, but it's good that you pointed it out.
Krish NAik: Very, few people use it. Again, underrated, SL.
Krish NAik: Lamini.
Krish NAik: LAIN law, then mini.
Krish NAik: Lamuni.
Krish NAik: Here's in the next batch, because you guys already have a good idea about RAG now, four fundamental things already, like, once we cover this batch, then certain things of RAG are much more. So, RAG plus LLM batch that I'll be…
Krish NAik: And focus on fine-tuning. Fine-tuning is really a big concept, so…
Krish NAik: before that, just be sure, because I'll be telling you, like.
Krish NAik: 50%, that's why I'll be working on that, and 50% inputs that I'll be taking.
Krish NAik: strengthening… Okay, then again, building foundational models, those things.
Krish NAik: Lamini is not an LLM mud thusal.
Krish NAik: Your son is 11.
Krish NAik: I'm a very old one.
Krish NAik: I've used it back, I think, around 2020.
Krish NAik: 3… Somewhere around that time, 2023 or 2024?
Krish NAik: Not last year, last to last year, that's all.
Krish NAik: In the new batch, also, of generative AI, I think Sunny has kept maintaining.
Krish NAik: The main problem is for fine-tuning. If you are not doing it by yourself, then it doesn't make sense if I do it and just show you how to do it.
Krish NAik: Because there are so many frameworks right now. Unslot, the easiest one, then you have Axotil, you have Llama Factory, you have DeepSpeed.
Krish NAik: Okay, you have, segal and so many things outcomes.
Krish NAik: Memorial different, memorized.
Krish NAik: Okay, Naga has shared one paper. Law LLM, Law, Large Language Model for Serious Legal. Okay, alright. They have the data on top of the data that they have built.
Krish NAik: Similarly, financial models are also available.
Krish NAik: Mmm…
Krish NAik: Okay, Pritham has asked me how to manage the context. There's a risk of context and data gets invalid with time and events.
Krish NAik: Alright, so generally, the context data, you need to handle it based on previous interactions.
Krish NAik: or past conversations.
Krish NAik: Now, how you are dividing, there are multiple ways.
Krish NAik: Like, do you want to mix your user profiling with your past conversations and that everything? We do handle that.
Krish NAik: And though we do keep a limit also, those to, like, at least 15,000 tokens, 20,000 tokens under that particular condition.
Krish NAik: Because with respect to time, you need to handle it.
Krish NAik: Probably, those updates come based on logic, and the logic is based on conversations, how the user is interacting with the system.
Krish NAik: If the user is working pretty much heavy, then probably, like, if a continuous session is going on, in that particular session, only you need to do context completion.
Krish NAik: Like, most of, ChatGPT model does it for you.
Krish NAik: Optimal number of tokens generally referred to as, like, 12,000 to 20,000 is a good number, we should anywhere around that.
Krish NAik: You can keep the range smaller also, but I feel that with respect to time, it increases only. Initially, it can be small. You can keep it smaller, but it will increase with respect to time.
Krish NAik: Guys, I think.
Krish NAik: I'm taking only questions.
Krish NAik: Can we use Mongo instead of VectorDB? Mongo means pure Mongo?
Krish NAik: pure Mongo, because you have Mongo vector search.
Krish NAik: Sorry. But directly, I cannot say that on top of your NoSQL, like, you know, Perform semantic search.
Krish NAik: Mongo vector switch you can use, then it's fine, fine.
Krish NAik: Mongo vectors such as mine.
Krish NAik: I think yesterday's video, Krish, did anybody look into that, or at L26CI?
Krish NAik: That is, right now, the best database that I feel.
Krish NAik: In the market, which supports everything.
Krish NAik: Yesterday's videos of Krish.
Krish NAik: I think that, Coria can lead you.
Krish NAik: In YouTube, the video is here in YouTube.
Krish NAik: Can you send the YouTube link? Just go and search Krishna, you know, you will be getting…
Krish NAik: Oracle 26 AI.
Krish NAik: This is one day ago, this is the video that I'm talking about.
Krish NAik: Thank you for doing it.
Krish NAik: So, this is, really good. It supports a lot of things.
Krish NAik: I've…
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's start with the…
Krish NAik: Next part of our discussion.
Krish NAik: I gang…
Krish NAik: First of all, let's start with, CRAG. I think CRAG will be fine. Okay, now, what's the paper? Okay, let me just get the link to the paper.
Krish NAik: In live class 2, gene ID is equal to 9.
Krish NAik: Amar Srinibas, you are asking… I'm not sure about exactly which one, let me check.
Krish NAik: First act, generative AI bootcamp the modern route, yes.
Krish NAik: This, you can do it. It has the fundamentals, but not entirely deep learning fundamentals.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think this only sunny will take, no? I think it will start from March 8.
Krish NAik: The enrollments have started for this month.
Krish NAik: This, curriculum… this code definition.
Krish NAik: It has a lot of things, but again, detailing with respect to RAG is much more generic generative AI.
Krish NAik: That is the main part. That's why you have a little bit of fine tuning, little bit of… everything is there.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is the paper that we'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think everybody is preferring, like, my morning slot is booked. Bank is free, so I think Sunny's morning slot, Mona's morning slot, all the morning slots are booked.
Krish NAik: That will be morning only.
Krish NAik: I don't think, it'll be night.
Krish NAik: The last, batch we took, it was late, so this time it will be money.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the paper. Let's go through. A lot of Chinese names are here.
Krish NAik: Ich, so… Major Leaf, the research, okay, so…
Krish NAik: As you can see, center of speech, language.
Krish NAik: University China Department, Google DeepMind, okay, UCLA.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a corrective rag, you call it CRAG also. The implementation is pretty much simple. Now, here, let's go through the abstract, and later on you can go through the entire paper.
Krish NAik: So, here, it's telling that large language models inevitably exhibit hallucinations since the accuracy of the generated text cannot be secured solely by the parametric knowledge they encapsulate.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think everybody remembers.
Krish NAik: Non-parametric and parametric, those things we have discussed in our initial sessions.
Krish NAik: AI, though, like, although RAG is a practical complement to LLMs, it relies heavily on the relevance of retrieval documents, raising the concerns how the model behaved if the retrieval goes wrong.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we knew in trying. If the retrieval goes wrong, it means that you'll be getting bad output.
Krish NAik: Okay, so to this end, we propose
Krish NAik: corrective RAG, okay, or CRAG, to improve the robustness of generations. So, specifically, a light retriever evaluator is designed to access the overall
Krish NAik: quality of retrieved documents for a query, returning a confidence degree based on which different knowledge retrieval actions can be triggered. Okay, so generally, just think about if you have
Krish NAik: If you have asked a query, okay, and based on that query, you didn't find any relevant information.
Krish NAik: from your vector database, then what the RAG system should do.
Krish NAik: Again, I'm repeating. If you have made a query to your RAG system.
Krish NAik: And from the vector databases, it could not get a single relevant chunk.
Krish NAik: Then what it should do.
Krish NAik: Puna was asking, hallucinate.
Krish NAik: Somebody's telling me, change the query. Alright, that's fine, just think about, even if you change the query, if it is not available.
Krish NAik: Then go to the LNN.
Krish NAik: No. Directly, don't go to that.
Krish NAik: First, a web search. An external, search is required.
Krish NAik: Nearest possible outcome. What is the nearest, now Buddhit, when you say, generate the nearest possible outcome. Who will do the generation?
Krish NAik: If you say LLM, finally it means that you are throwing it back to the LLM only, no?
Krish NAik: But before that LLM. Just think about if the LLM doesn't have
Krish NAik: that information, from where it can fetch. It's only the width.
Krish NAik: That's why the fallback is web search. That is basically the trigger that they are referring here.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, here, specifically a light…
Krish NAik: Weight Retrieval evaluated. So, who will do the evaluation?
Krish NAik: LLM, okay? It's designed to access the overall quality of retrieved documents for a query.
Krish NAik: Returning a confidence degree based on which different knowledge retrieval actions that can be triggered. Since the retrieval from static and limited corpora can only return suboptimal documents, large-scale web searches are utilized as an extension for augmenting the retrieval results.
Krish NAik: So that's why it's very specifically mentioned here. Lars-scale web searches.
Krish NAik: So, simply on web search.
Krish NAik: And you have different type of web search tools. For example, DuckDuckGo is there, then you have BraveSearch, then you have
Krish NAik: Sharper API, web, like, Google Search you can do. Then you can use very specifically, like, agent-bit systems, like, Tableau is there, then you have ExaSearch.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, so many types of search.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, Muhammad, is telling no sense related to what that you have written, no sense.
Krish NAik: If the score is low, we still can go to externally? Yes, yes, you can put a simple confidence logic. If something is less than 0.2, 0.3, based on that particular scoring, also, you can go to your external. It can be Wikipedia, it can be anything, like an external trigger.
Krish NAik: Now Dinesh is asking, even if there's not good, need to go to web search, alright?
Krish NAik: You need to go to web search only, or go to regenerate the query and do… no, no, no, no, not about… just think about… probably, you have done everything. It means that you did a query transformation, then also you did not
Krish NAik: fetch anything in your vector team, and it is a very common case.
Krish NAik: That's why, A, everybody who is building OpenAI Anthropic, they rely heavily on external tools.
Krish NAik: To perform web search.
Krish NAik: Because the… whatever, any model that is getting released in the market, they have a cut-off trading date.
Krish NAik: It means that after that, they have zero idea.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, this is the second stage retrieval.
Krish NAik: We don't call it the second stage, but it's a fallback condition, simply, that you can say.
Krish NAik: If you really think in that, it's a yes-to stage. The first stage failed, then in the second stage, the fallback will take place. So, it's saying that besides, decompose, then recompose algorithm is designed for retrick documents.
Krish NAik: To selectively focus on key information and filter out irrelevant information in them. CRAG is plug-and-play and can be seamlessly coupled with various RAG-based approaches.
Krish NAik: Experiments with four datasets covering short- and long-form generation tasks show that CRAC can significantly improve the performance of RAC-based approaches.
Krish NAik: So here, what is the main purpose of bringing CRAG into the system? Can I say that again, improving your…
Krish NAik: A retrieval quality, because we are introducing a lightweight retriever… a retrieval evaluator.
Krish NAik: So here, the entire game lies on the retrieval. Similarly, in the next paper, the entire game lies on the generation.
Krish NAik: Because now the question is, In simple terms, if I see what is the main question, or what is…
Krish NAik: Now, is your retrieval correct or not? In simple terms, I can say.
Krish NAik: And for that, the response is, see that. This is the main thing that the paper tries. Because triggers, right now, they are, heavily relied on web search, because yes, if
Krish NAik: If you ask something which is totally out of the context of VectorDB, then for sure, that is the final solution, which is basically a web search call that you'll be making.
Krish NAik: Now, Sai Bhumana is calling, so LLM will call… no, no, no, no, no. See, I will call the web search tool, whichever tool that I will see. Right now, I'm calling it a tool, it's a simple call. Probably, like, you can use a package like DuckDuckGo, Brave Search, Tagal, XR, so many types of search.
Krish NAik: engines are there, okay? Or, like, Google search directly.
Krish NAik: Fire crawl, so many things. Now, from there.
Krish NAik: Once you get that particular context, that particular context, you will be sending it to the LLM. So the LLM won't be making that call.
Krish NAik: Okay, I hope I have made that point clear.
Krish NAik: Now, Aruna is asking if the LLM does not understand how the LLM provides confident level.
Krish NAik: If the LLM does not understand what it will not understand? Aruna.
Krish NAik: I'm not directly getting the response from the LLM, I'm using an external tool, I'm searching some type of context, that particular context, I'm sending it to the LLM.
Krish NAik: So the LLM knows what are the knowledge sources. It will be having the ground truths, the URL from where it has
Krish NAik: Fetch that particular data.
Krish NAik: It means that I'm building my new context in simple terms.
Krish NAik: that new context, I'm passing it.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you are telling that, even if the web search fails.
Krish NAik: Yes, there can be a condition, even when the web search that comes. AdaptiveRag will come after that round.
Krish NAik: Okay, so those adaptive logo characters are the same.
Krish NAik: It's a combination, much more of SRAC and CRAC, but yes, the advancement is adapted now.
Krish NAik: So, initially, we are starting with CRAG and SRAG, then we will move to Adaptive RAG.
Krish NAik: Little bit different. AdaptiveGrag is a little bit different.
Krish NAik: But, pretty much the same stuff.
Krish NAik: More than 70% similarities are there.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: With the self-diagnosis notes along the lang… okay, if you talk from Langrah perspective, that is correct.
Krish NAik: From Langrav, that is… that is, you have a special self-diagnosis, or that's why, like, a self-healing mood that you have.
Krish NAik: Now, what if some junk sent into, sent a query? What if some junk…
Krish NAik: sent a query to the LLM.
Krish NAik: What if some junk? Okay, alright. Now, probably, based on that particular query, let's take the example you are not doing any transformations.
Krish NAik: Based on the query, probably in that query you were telling, there is a lot of junk. Fine. Now, based on that, you passed it, and then you didn't get any context.
Krish NAik: Now, in this type of cases, like, somehow, you need to do query transformations if you feel that, if you have a lot of junk. Let's remove the junk for now, through query transformation.
Krish NAik: And then, even if I try to pass to the retriever, Naga, and if I don't get any response from the retriever.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the main thing. So, here they are talking about
Krish NAik: Majorly, all the LLMs are much more focused towards the parametric knowledge, what comes, anything that is non-parametric due to nature.
Krish NAik: How to handle that. To handle that, you need some type of external knowledge basis, and that external knowledge basis that they are referring as, like, web search.
Krish NAik: Large-scale web search that they have returned.
Krish NAik: Related to what, Raul?
Krish NAik: You can paste that link. Web search will be fetching the result not related to the context, so… no, see, the idea is whenever you are, doing a web search.
Krish NAik: it will try to fetch the context from to the URLs, so it will be making the new context and passing it to the LLM, rather than from the vector team.
Krish NAik: Like, Wiki retrieval, correct, Wikipedia retrieval, or something like tools.
Krish NAik: The external knowledge can be anything. It can be an API call or anything.
Krish NAik: there, based on that, even, like, if you have very specific keywords, like Wikipedia, or archived papers, or something like that, I can redirect it to a specific API call, or archive, or to Wikipedia, or through that.
Krish NAik: That is… that will be a custom… that's why. This is a custom retriever in simple terms, okay?
Krish NAik: Now, after getting the context from the web, do we pass it to the… no, no, no. Once we get it from the con… Like, once we fetch the context from the web, we pass it to the LL.
Krish NAik: Nothing, no VectorDB connections.
Krish NAik: Okay, nothing related to VectorDB here.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, so this is what a simple example that they have kept it, if you really look here. What, is Henry, Fielden's occupation, and who was the screenwriter for Death of a Batman? Based on the retribut, you can see these are the current documents which are being written, okay, and these are the incorrect documents.
Krish NAik: Now, these correct documents, okay, simply, like, this is a middleman right now, because the next step is pass it to the generator.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is a correct one, that in simple terms, this is the politician from here, I can see, the main occupation. But here, if really, like Batman, here you can see that you are not getting that context, so simply it has been classified as a ham.
Krish NAik: ham, like, spam or ham, okay, that, particular. Ham is, right now, junk only. If junk goes into the…
Krish NAik: Generator, what will come out of the generator? That will also be junk.
Krish NAik: Preetam C is asking, but external content is always there with the LLM, so why not fall back? Preetam, external content is there, but that content is limited to a cut-off training date.
Krish NAik: I'm not telling that LLMs don't have external, they do have external, but they have a limitation, no? Reetham, I hope you get my point.
Krish NAik: If you ask it, what is the weather?
Krish NAik: Today, do you think that the LLM will have any idea about today's weather?
Krish NAik: Of a particular location that you are passing Preetam.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Now…
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, like, if your retrieval quality is bad, for sure there will be hallucinations, but that's why all those things with respect to hallucinations that have been mentioned here, and with respect to Iraq.
Krish NAik: Okay,
Krish NAik: Now, yes, sir, using reference than training. Using reference than training. Training? Like, how training comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: Because I'm, like, using reference from web searches, that is the main priority.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, overview of our model inference. Let's talk about this ritual evaluator.
Krish NAik: Okay, so can you see here? This is the main architecture of CRAT.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, learn.
Krish NAik: Lakshmi is telling you how it is different for multimodal. Multimodal is different. That is text, image, video. Right now, we are only talking with respect to text only.
Krish NAik: Lakshmi, I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: Multimodal is a totally different topic, it's out of the context that you were telling right now.
Krish NAik: Now, the retrieval part?
Krish NAik: Any type of question that you will be asking based on that question, it will be retrieving some documents from the vector DB.
Krish NAik: Okay, now they have attached a knowledge correction module that they are referring right now in this particular paper. Okay, so after this knowledge correction module only, it will go to the generation phase.
Krish NAik: So, right now, they have created 3 different type of categories. So, simply, the retrieval evaluator is asking a question. Ask, if the retriever documents are correct to X, what if X? X is basically the query?
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, here, what they are telling, they have created 3 separate tags, okay, or 3 separate categories. One is the correct category, one is the ambiguous category, one is the incorrect. If you look into the correct category, I will say that, okay, you are getting correct responses from VectorD.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, based on D1 and D2, let's talk about D1 and D2 are two different types of charts. So here, in the correct phase, the knowledge refinement. So D1 with D2,
Krish NAik: Alright, now D1 and D2, then they are performing a decomposition operation. Now, from this D1 and D2, they are actually breaking it into much more smaller strips, step 1, strip 2, Strip K.
Krish NAik: Now, on top of that, if you try to apply some type of filters… now, this is where refinement… so generally, during the refinement process, we make things much more smaller. So that's why the main chunk has been broken into smaller things.
Krish NAik: Now, from here, probably, like, strip 1 to K, so after the filtration, based on your query, I can say that yes, and then again, a re… Recompose. It means that from those broken things, again, you are creating
Krish NAik: A bigger information.
Krish NAik: Now…
Krish NAik: This is the mean… see, if you really look into this diagram, the retrieval evaluator, and here it has kept it. So, the filter logic is applied on top of the scripts. Okay, and finally, from there, whatever the refined strips that you are getting.
Krish NAik: The list of scripts will be recomposed to be your final knowledge.
Krish NAik: from your vector TV.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is a step with respect to knowledge refinement. Now comes knowledge searching. Knowledge search simply means web search, there is nothing new.
Krish NAik: Rewrite. Okay, now, Death of the Batman, screenwriter, Wikipedia, directory, do a web search, if it is known. And there is a condition of using both. It means that this is the ambiguous term.
Krish NAik: In ambiguous, what happens, okay, it can go into this particular direction, in this particular direction also. So, it can trigger your main, knowledge, refinement pipeline, as well as your knowledge search.
Krish NAik: If you feel that, the confidence score of your, during ambiguous, we keep it around, like, 0.4, between 0.7.
Krish NAik: Okay, correct means above 0.7, and incorrect means always 0. less than 0.3. In that way, you can build your own scoring systems, and based on that, you can, do it. Now, I will say that
Krish NAik: This is a good approach.
Krish NAik: But again, a lot of things that comes into the picture, like, strips.
Krish NAik: When you talk about strips, So, what do you mean by scripts?
Krish NAik: Can I say that smaller sentences and simple?
Krish NAik: Somebody's telling smaller chunks, okay. Now, just think about, if you have a single sentence only in the chunk, then what will happen?
Krish NAik: Do you think stripping is possible in those cases?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, word… we don't break it into words, not possible.
Krish NAik: Because if I look into words, the entire semantic meaning context is gone.
Krish NAik: Okay, the resume. So, like, that's why I'm telling you, like, here, really, with respect to scripts, that plays a crucial role.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that simply, like, directly don't think about if I have something, because D1 and D2 are actual vector dB chunk. But if your chunk is small, then this particular thing cannot be applied. So that's why I'm telling you on condition, because in this paper, really, it means that they have taken that by default, 500.
Krish NAik: With the latest chunking strategies, okay, it can feel also.
Krish NAik: Because if you are maintaining, like, same chunks, you maintain chunking, in that same chunking, if you maintain the boundaries, and if you have a single sentence within a chunk.
Krish NAik: Then, simply, like, this particular condition doesn't count.
Krish NAik: Into the picture.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then, you have your, knowledge search.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is component. Now, from here, whatever, based on that particular conditioning, you can see here, if it is correct, find X plus K. What is K?
Krish NAik: Right now, this is the final K in.
Krish NAik: In means internal data source that you have, which is VectorDB.
Krish NAik: Then comes EX, means external. So, internal and external, that… in that way, they have done. So, X plus, and by default, you have to understand, this always happens in a default rack system.
Krish NAik: The first one is correct one. This condition always happens. You don't have to do it. This is by default how RAG works.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, now Rahul is telling D1 and D2 are decomposed. What type of filters are applied to recompose?
Krish NAik: Are there predefined quotes, you will be using certain template lists. Once you have those decomposed parts, then again, I'm paraphrasing using those existing strips.
Krish NAik: They are, like, D1 and D2 are decomposed, it means that the bigger chunk is composed into smaller chunk or smaller sentences for now. Because actually, in a chunk, you might have 4 to 5 sentences, 6 sentences, 8 sentences, not bigger than that. It totally depends upon your chances.
Krish NAik: Now, once you have done that, this trip can be… a lot of sentences can be there. But, the question comes, what about a single sentence that way? Once you have those sentences, you can again reframe. So, simple concatenation operation with complete rephrasing, and maintaining the same, context. So, through a prompt template, you can do that.
Krish NAik: So, Muthasara's asking, when does it identify, or rather, how does it identify when to take, how does… through an LLM call? That will be decided by the LLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, so when I'll be showing you the implementation, then I'll be showing all these things
Krish NAik: Like, you can ask an LLM to do this for you.
Krish NAik: There is no benefit, really. If you feel that you are getting exactly the correct result, then it's fine. This is the first condition.
Krish NAik: Okay, Motaza, like, what is the benefit of that knowledge refinement, really? I would say there is not a lot of added benefit. In most of the implementations of CRAT, they directly pick it from VectorDB. They don't apply scripts and other things. It's pretty much, if you really look into implementations of original
Krish NAik: I can say Sirug also, in the paper, they are mad at it, but actually, everywhere we'll be using the chunks only.
Krish NAik: Because for that, again, how many LLM calls you will make it, you have to think in that perspective.
Krish NAik: Because this is always adding a bottleneck. First, do a decomposition, then again, do a recomposition. Nobody does it.
Krish NAik: Okay, practically, nobody does, because this doesn't actually make sense. First, recompose and decompose, certain conditions, only this is good. But most of the times, if you have made your rag in such a way, because right now, the idea is what?
Krish NAik: Main one is this knowledge search.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I feel that this is actually an added bottleneck. First, you do a decomposition, and then you perform a recomposition.
Krish NAik: Because at the end of the day, you are trying to do a complete rephrasing, having the same, similar context.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, see, here in that way, I can say, if you think about one added benefit, only one benefit that I really see here, which is
Krish NAik: Making your context much more smaller.
Krish NAik: That is only the added benefit. It means that in D1 and D2, there were, let's take 50 and 50 sentences. Okay, so from there, strip happened, like, let's take you have 100 sentences. Now, out of those 100 sentences, it filtered only 10 sentences.
Krish NAik: I hope you get my point. Like, the added benefit here of refinement. It means that you are passing lesser information.
Krish NAik: And much more focusing on that. That is the mean idea.
Krish NAik: But again, and added bottleneck, because this is one level, if you really think about, once you break the chunks into strips, this is one level of filter on top of data. Some level of context compression, can I say?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because this is one level of context compression only.
Krish NAik: You are actually picking up very selected scripts based on the filter of your query.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And then, using those steps only, you are creating your final job.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's move to the next part. The next part is the knowledge source, so that's right, majorly.
Krish NAik: I can say more than 60% of the time, the correct condition is applied, then comes ambiguous. In ambiguous, what you take, you take the query also, you take the information from VectorDB also, and you take the information from external list source also. So here, you take vectorDB information as well as external. When you feel that.
Krish NAik: I'm not confident.
Krish NAik: It means that your confidence level is close to 50% confidence only. So that's why this condition, you can keep it according to scoring mechanisms. I'll be showing you that implementation, but you can, like, make it a call. So, according to that, value that you will be deciding, based on that value, you can apply the logic.
Krish NAik: Apply all those three things. And incorrect means you have no option, you have to use only web search.
Krish NAik: Okay, and right now, in web search K1, K2, K, what are these?
Krish NAik: These are the result of the URLs, or basically the web pages that got fetched by your tool.
Krish NAik: Abhishek, it will give good results, but will add latency, yes, for sure, if you apply anything, because this is, some type of, I can say.
Krish NAik: a condition where you actually added one level of retrieval, evaluator. But again, this is lightweight, so for sure the LLM call, we will try to keep it smaller, but if you really try to think on this particular condition, because to do the recomposition.
Krish NAik: Just think about, if you are breaking, like, 50-50 total, then scripting operation. Just think about, in this particular stripper, you are using a sentence tokenization operation.
Krish NAik: It means that, let's leave I'm not using any LLM, I'm just trying to break it purely based on her code logic.
Krish NAik: Okay, I can do that, we know.
Krish NAik: So, simply, it's like, sentence has been done. Now, this part, and once I have done the filter of these scripts. So, can I say that this is another? Because when I'm doing a filter, the filter has to be based on what?
Krish NAik: Can I say it's specific to query only, yes or no?
Krish NAik: It has been based on query.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here it means that
Krish NAik: Am I doing some type of offline similarity search?
Krish NAik: On top of those 100 sentences, previously it was X amount of chunks.
Krish NAik: Probably 1,000, 2,000 chunks, but again, one level of that. So, little bit latency that comes into the system, that is fine.
Krish NAik: Because even if this condition arrives, then also latency, even this condition arrives, there's also latency. Because for your API call, first it will get the URL, then from the URL it will fetch the content, that way it will get it.
Krish NAik: Now, I will say that, this is good, like, in a simple system, always it's good, like, the fallback condition needs to be applied.
Krish NAik: Okay, because most of the RAC systems won't have anything, like, any information about your external data.
Krish NAik: Okay, so majorly, you can rely to a, like, a fallback system to web search. But if you feel that, yes, external search is not required, then don't use it simply.
Krish NAik: Then you have to say that, yes.
Krish NAik: My system doesn't have any information about the query that you have asked.
Krish NAik: So, very specifically, that will be the return type of your system.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is… so here it's telling that an overview of the proposed CRAG at inference. A retrieval evaluator is constructed to evaluate the relevance of the retrieval documents to the input and estimate a confidence degree based on which different knowledge retrieval actions, like correct, incorrect, ambiguous, can be triggered.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here it's saying that our objective is to correctly retrieve the documents if they are relevant. So, in this particular condition, they have specifically used T5 large. Okay, so T5. What is T5? What type of model is T5?
Krish NAik: Yes, guys?
Krish NAik: What type of model is keyframe?
Krish NAik: No, no, not a GPU model. No, no, guys. Transformers model, everybody knows.
Krish NAik: Transformers means it is based on attention, self-attention. Yes, the actual thing I was looking for, sequence to sequence, or you guys might say encoder-to-decoder. Okay, so encoding and decoding.
Krish NAik: update.
Krish NAik: Because there are a few families, and majorly, here you know the input is a sequence of tokens, the output is also a sequence-to- like, output is also a sequence of tokens. So this is a sequence-to-sequence task. So that's why T5, you have, then E family, part family.
Krish NAik: So many families are at the Mariam MD,
Krish NAik: And RAG is actually a sequence-to-sequence model.
Krish NAik: How many of you think
Krish NAik: Because I don't know, in 2022 and 2023, because the RAG idea came. But that time, people used to call RAG as a model.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in that RAG, they used to call it… because RAG is actually a sequence-to-sequence model, if you think.
Krish NAik: How many of you agree?
Krish NAik: on that
Krish NAik: If I say RAG is a sequence-to-sequence model, how many of you agree on that?
Krish NAik: She says, let me know, yes, no, at least let me know your thoughts.
Krish NAik: Can't recall already.
Krish NAik: It's encoded to decoder.
Krish NAik: In our case, also, we take a query, we perform the encoding.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, and even the decoding
Krish NAik: that happens, it's through cosine similarity? Okay.
Krish NAik: So, yes, Raj is actually an…
Krish NAik: we call secret the sequence. So, if I show you some…
Krish NAik: Back in 2022, because RAG is treated as a sequence-to-SQLS model, All right.
Krish NAik: And now, Here, something, because the self-rac paper came first, and
Krish NAik: Self-RAB, again, will be coming to that, but, really you can look into that, and this is the algorithm that they have taken into account. Okay, so the CRAG inference, require an retrieval evaluator. Then comes your query rewriter, can you see here? W?
Krish NAik: Then comes your G generator, which is basically the LLM. Then you parse your input X, which is the input quotient. D is equal to D1, D2, the retrieve documents. From there, you'll be getting your output Y.
Krish NAik: Now, score that we are defining evaluates the relevance of each pair, XD.
Krish NAik: Okay, so X means your query D, so based on that, multiple scores that will be generated. Then comes calculate the confidence. So, calculate and give a final judgment based on score 1, score 2, till score K.
Krish NAik: So K means the total number of chunks that you are actually creating the pair for.
Krish NAik: The confidence has three, optional values. One is correct, one is incorrect, one is ambiguous. You have to select. Now, if confidence is equal to correct, then internal knowledge is equal to knowledge refinement known. So, X comma D, and K is equal to internal knowledge. If
Krish NAik: Confidence is equal to incorrect, then what? External knowledge source is equal to web search, this definition, and K is equal to this.
Krish NAik: And if it is ambiguous, call both the sources. So, finally, your K is a combination. This is a pseudo-put that they have written.
Krish NAik: Okay? So this is a pseudocode of the algorithm that needs to be implemented.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, here they have, talked about the action triggers right here.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me see the motion link that Rahul has shared.
Krish NAik: There is no access route, okay?
Krish NAik: This is the, correct, incorrect. The same things, like, you can go through this entire paper. I will say that it's a one-time read, it's an interesting one, because with respect to corrective something, then you already know the algorithm. If you know the algorithm.
Krish NAik: The theoretical part you can easily understand. So here, let me just go through the correct part. Here, a retrieval is assumed correct when the confidence score of at least one retrieval document is higher than the upper threshold.
Krish NAik: So, generally, what happens when you are performing a cosine similarity operation on top of your vector databases?
Krish NAik: Can I say that there can be a condition where the first chunk cosine civility value was higher, and the rest two?
Krish NAik: Are very, very low.
Krish NAik: Can there be a condition?
Krish NAik: Just think.
Krish NAik: If I say… because right now, I'm telling based on cosine similarity. If you really feel that those two chunks
Krish NAik: are really, like, having very less cosine score. It means that simply I can ignore those two chunks, and I can only focus only once.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is also one level of refinement that can be actually taken from this.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here it, talking about, so it means that there are relevant documents in the retrieved results, and the knowledge from the retrieved result is supposed to be more reliable and accurate. However, even if a relevant document can be found, there is inevitably some noisy knowledge steps in this document.
Krish NAik: now they are talking about, okay, within that particular chunk, there can be some type of noise. To extract the most critical knowledge within this document, a knowledge refinement method is further designed, which is actually breaking into stuff. Now, from those broken chunks, you pick up which one is the best one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so similarly, your incorrect is directly falling back to web search, nothing, and ambiguous is a combination of correct as well as incorrect.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, let's focus on this particular paragraph of knowledge refinement. Their implementation scene. Anything, something written in paper, and then the actual implementation which is available, because I think CRAG implementation is…
Krish NAik: not available in Lansion, but I think CRAG implementation is levelable in Lama Index.
Krish NAik: I did it, last year, I didn't have checked this here, but again, I'll be showing you that part. So here, with respect to knowledge refinement, they are telling, given a retrieved relevant document.
Krish NAik: Decompose… then recompose the knowledge refinement method is designed to further extract the most critical knowledge strips in it. To obtain, fine-grained retrieval results, we segmented the retrieval result into internal strips.
Krish NAik: Okay, and now internal scripts means you can think about scripts are referred to much more sentences. If a retrieve result is as short as 1 or 2 sentences.
Krish NAik: It is regarded as an individual script. Now, they have taken a condition. If the chunk size is small, then let's chunk as a strip. So, your chunk will actually be a single strip. Otherwise, the retrieval documents are required to be split into smaller units, which generally consist of few sentences according to the total length.
Krish NAik: The scale is assumed to include an independent piece of information, and the filtering is based on these segments.
Krish NAik: Then the retrieval evaluator, fine-tuned in section 4.0 is employed to calculate the relevant score. Okay, it means that you have a specific retrieval evaluator which will be doing the scoring. So, based on the scores, we categorize it as irrelevant knowledge strips, which are filtered out, and we only take the relevant ones.
Krish NAik: And then we recompose it via concatenation that only I told, in order, namely, the internal merge.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in this way. But always remember, when you do this operation, you lose some type of…
Krish NAik: That information, because… Order matters to us, and if you remove something from the order.
Krish NAik: Really, like, there will be some amount of impact. The quality somehow will degrades. I cannot say it will be very good, but somehow better.
Krish NAik: That's the thing, because whenever you are doing something, everything has a cone.
Krish NAik: The pro is better, the corn is less, in this case.
Krish NAik: It might weaken the context for sure, Muhammad. Because if you try to remove the strips, for sure, it will weaken the context.
Krish NAik: That's why in everybody's research paper, they don't write the bad things about their implementation. They only focus on the good things.
Krish NAik: How to find the thresholds for the confidence, Aruna will be defining that, you know, by ourselves, in our scoring mechanism. So, you have these three categories correct, I will say anything more than 0.7.
Krish NAik: Then for the other one, I will say ambitious means 0.3 to 0.7 or 0.4. And then, if something is, like, really incorrect, that particular condition, below 0. In that way, I will be telling.
Krish NAik: Are we deciding the scores? No, LLM will do that.
Krish NAik: Alright, so different type of experiments with PopQ, PubHealth, ARP Challenge that they have done. Okay, and right now, web search, any type of web search. So, here much more with respect to which tool that they have used.
Krish NAik: large-scale web searches, 2021-2022, integrated as part of the extension operator.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, now guys, let's focus, because majorly, if we look into, for sure, if you try to implement that, so here they have taken Llama 2, ChatGPT, okay, Red ChatGPT, Perplexity, again, like, PopKeyway, based on those,
Krish NAik: some level of improvements, I can say, into certain systems, but again, not everywhere. So, baselines with all the retrieval, the quality is towards the lower side. Okay, LLM screened with proprietary data, yes, you have good ones.
Krish NAik: Now, here, if I try to bring your CRAG into the picture, Is that so C-rag?
Krish NAik: Yes, I can say the base label retrieval, at least. The original standard track was providing close to 50.5,
Krish NAik: This is a baseline retrieval. That has increased here to 54.9, so I can see. Cell prag really… see, cell prag has a different purpose, so it has nothing related to your retrieval.
Krish NAik: So, it's fine. And then, a combination of self-reg with CRAG.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is around 49. So, you can see here, really, the combination… okay, so better CRAG is linked.
Krish NAik: Now, here's self-rag with Llama. Here, also, you can look into the CRAT.
Krish NAik: 59.8, but again, the combination of cell, rag with CRAG here worked better. So really, like, it totally depends upon the model, okay, and exactly on top of which you are actually doing it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so standard RAG, okay, so these are some, references based on the models with, like, Llama 2,
Krish NAik: Hugging Face 7 billion model that they have picked up, and for sure, the scores will increase if they are going with higher models. 7M… the 7 million model is good to test with, because that is much more lightweight version.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think now we can start looking into the implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I think,
Krish NAik: In LangChain, a direct implementation is not there in Llama Index, and check that part. Llama Index, CRAG work looks like. Previously, I was looking for that one, only as corrective rag workflow.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there is a direct, implementation which is, directly available here.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So through this, and right now, as you can see, they have used Taveli for this particular workflow.
Krish NAik: Okay, but yes, they have a specific class, the corrective rack workflow class. So this implementation you can check, because each implementation will be different. It's not like…
Krish NAik: It is a direct copy-paste of the research paper.
Krish NAik: In Langrav also, somehow it will be different, so… But…
Krish NAik: Let's focus on the implementation that we do have.
Krish NAik: So, let's do a save.
Krish NAik: I think you guys will be having the access to CRAT.
Krish NAik: Check once.
Krish NAik: I think, I have shared that notebook. Please do have a check.
Krish NAik: Now, Rahul, you were asking Notion Link… Notion, understanding… Lovely.
Krish NAik: Yes, now, this is a flu.
Krish NAik: Generally, when we are working with nodes, this is a better one.
Krish NAik: So, because right now, I'm not working with nodes. These are directly available in the Langra… Rapun.
Krish NAik: The workflow is exactly the same, there is no difference.
Krish NAik: the same workflow that we have defined. You pass a question, then related to index, it goes to the vector store. Otherwise, it goes to the web search-based events. Anything else, like, directly the answer goes to the LL. Actually, this web search should be fed here.
Krish NAik: So directly, again, this implementation is different, not directly on top of that. And on top of that, they have combined your rack plus self-reflection. So this is a combination of both the things in this particular image.
Krish NAik: It's not a unique image, this is the actual image which, from… it has been taken from the core. Because if you look into the Langraf repo, the same modules of SRAG, CRAG with Langraf implementation that you can get it.
Krish NAik: In your image, the self-rag part is also there. But we have not discussed self-rag.
Krish NAik: And, that implementation, like, really, even right now, I'm not taught Langra. Later on, with respect to Langra app, I think direct notebooks are there.
Krish NAik: The Langchen community has done that.
Krish NAik: If you want, you can take that, reference if you know Langrov. I think, Langrov… Notebooks.
Krish NAik: Hmm… Oh, I think. In this one, you have those notebooks of those.
Krish NAik: I'm thinking of which one? Last month, LG1…
Krish NAik: Probably they might have updated to the RFO, but again, in Langshan, direct implementations are a bluep
Krish NAik: Because the creator of Langchain only did these things, so we can look.
Krish NAik: Perfect, so…
Krish NAik: Where is R1? Yes.
Krish NAik: Now, what I've done, you can directly open the notebook, okay? So, just install an extension. So, right now, I've, provided the DuckDuckGo, okay? Now, this, through DuckDuckGo, I'll be making a call. Now, the calls will be limited, so I've not used any specific API key for DuckDuckGo.
Krish NAik: Okay, in free also, you can directly make a call, but if you feel that you have problem with respect to limits, please then get the key for Dr.co.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, the ideas don't make a lot of calls. That's the request. Otherwise, get a specific key from the truck.
Krish NAik: So, right now, I'm taking some external tools. One is the Google search run, one is the search results. So, two different type of tools. Actually, I'll be using the search results much more.
Krish NAik: So, right here, landscape core prompts. From here, I have taken the prompt template, then chat OpenAI, and then, defining the base model through which I can create some type of predict-based configurations.
Krish NAik: Now, some helper functions that I do have, so these helper functions, if you remember, one is used to read any type of document, and then I have the evaluate drag. Okay, now, these are some custom models.
Krish NAik: in the last, last month when I showed. So, one is, like, replace key with space, then you have text wrap. Encoding a PDF, it means that loading a PDF directly with PyPDFloader, encoding from a string, okay, and here, chunking. So, all these things, I've kept it separately in one place.
Krish NAik: And then you have this evaluate rack, so here, majorly, the implementations are with respect to DPVAT. But directly, I won't be using them right now, so don't worry about that.
Krish NAik: UBP install, rank BM25 is required. I don't think BM25 is required for this work now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so where was our seat, I guess?
Krish NAik: So, first of all, once I have, done the implementation, then let's create an instance for our, I think, where is our search tool? Yes. This is the search tool, the DuckDuckGo.
Krish NAik: then load ENV, and I'll be using the OKNA IP, so let me just try to load it.
Krish NAik: Then, this is a file that I am using. So, the climate change file, this file I've been using for a long time.
Krish NAik: So, I'll be just reading that. In your case, just check if you have it or not.
Krish NAik: If you don't have it, you can ask for the URL.
Krish NAik: What is DuckDuckGo?
Krish NAik: Dr.go is used for web search, moment. I can use any tool, Tablei, Exa, Brave Search, Google Search, anything. Now, here, I've taken just Dr. Go.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes creating a vector store. So, for the vector store, directly encode PDF, and I have passed the path. This is a custom function which is available in my help… helper functions inside the utils.
Krish NAik: No? Okay, so… I think this one…
Krish NAik: 1, 2, 3, let me just load it.
Krish NAik: Here, I'm passing the LLM initialization.
Krish NAik: Alright,
Krish NAik: I think this installation, if required in your case, please do it. Okay, because I was getting an error with respect to DC. So, this is Dr. DTGS. That is the package for Dr. Co.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just check. So, this part should work. If it is not working, please do the installation of ubweb install hyphen UDDGS.
Krish NAik: I'm sure in yours, we don't use it much. Fine, if you don't use… the idea was to show you anything. Later on, I can use Tableau also.
Krish NAik: For Google search, you can use Sherpa API if you want more.
Krish NAik: Now, defining the retrieval evaluator, the knowledge refinement, and the query retrywriter LLM. So, multiple LLM chains that I'll be building. So, first of all, let's focus on the first one. So, this is the main Retrieval evaluator.
Krish NAik: So, here…
Krish NAik: I'm inheriting from the base model of Pydantic. So here, I have defined the first one, which is the relevance score, which will be a float value, description the relevance score of the document to the query.
Krish NAik: score should be between 0 to 1. Now, here I have created my own function, def, retrieval, retriever.
Krish NAik: First of all, the query string.
Krish NAik: which the user will be passing. Then comes your document string, the list of documents that you have.
Krish NAik: Then comes prompt is equal to prompt template, input variables is equal to the query in the document.
Krish NAik: And right now in this, I'm giving a scale 0 to 1. Now, this particular template, in different conditions, it can be. So here, I've kept it simple, like, on a scale of 0 to 1. How relevant is the following document to the query?
Krish NAik: So, the query, and then the list of the documents, and based on that, it will provide you the relevant score. So, this is your scoring logic that we have applied it here. Now, based on your scoring decision, you can add more information.
Krish NAik: Like, you can provide some examples also.
Krish NAik: Then comes your chain. I'm building the chain prompt with LLM with structured output.
Krish NAik: And then I am passing my retrieval evaluator input, the input variables, my query, and the document, and I am invoking the chain. This is the first chain only for the retrieval part. So this is where we do the scoring.
Krish NAik: Half hour?
Krish NAik: or power chunks.
Krish NAik: whatever the chunks that have been fetched. Based on the query that we try to do the scoring of our chunk from the vector TB. So, query to that.
Krish NAik: Now, in the next part, what do I have the knowledge?
Krish NAik: refinement.
Krish NAik: Now, class, knowledge refinement input, again, I'm narrating the properties from the base model.
Krish NAik: And the major points here, so this is a field in the description, the document to extract key information from.
Krish NAik: Okay, the document to extract key information, it means that within the chunk, there will be some type of key information that we are assuming.
Krish NAik: Now, this knowledge refinement prompt, inside this, I've kept it, so the input will be, right now, a single list of documents.
Krish NAik: Then in the template, Extract the key information from the following document in bullet points.
Krish NAik: So, those are the actual strips. Extract the key information. So, in that way, in bullet points, it means that those are the actual core things. So, whenever I'm doing any extraction process, loss of information will be there.
Krish NAik: And based on that, the return type will be key points. Always remember, I've added, like, slash and slash in.
Krish NAik: In the, prompt.
Krish NAik: Okay, so rather than just keeping it as separate lines.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: again, creating the final chain using land chain, then passing the input variables, invoking the chain, and returning, based on the return type of the result, from there, extracting one by one. Because key points, so all these points will be based on slashing, slashing, slashing, okay?
Krish NAik: And then finally, once I have them, so all those scripts I'm looking for, so that's why in the paper, they have, talked about that stripping. But actually, from the result, you will be perform a split and then concatenation operation, which was that recomposing part.
Krish NAik: Now, comes your web search query rewriter. Now, again, the class that I have for my custom chain, dev rewrite query, and here I rewrite the following query to make it more suitable for a web search, rewrite them the query. Done.
Krish NAik: So, 3 simple classes that I have defined.
Krish NAik: Now, this implementation, I have kept it simpler. You can make it more complex going forward. Now, one is parse such results. So, what is the purpose of this?
Krish NAik: What is the purpose of this? Whenever you get the search results, those results will be passed.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that from the… any tool, those… from those tools, you will be getting the result. To parse those type of results, it is required, okay? So, helper function, just to parse your search-based results.
Krish NAik: So, immediately all the responses will be in JSON. Whenever you are working with DuckDuck Boat, Tavili, everyone throws you a response in the form of JSON.
Krish NAik: Now, defining some sub-functions for our CRAC process. So, first of all, the retrieval process for the document.
Krish NAik: This will be common one, query, files, index.
Krish NAik: That comes evaluation of the documents.
Krish NAik: This is my retrieval evaluated that I've defined above, which I'm using.
Krish NAik: Then, performing the web search.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here I'm using that particular parse search result function that I've defined. So, one by one, all those things that I'm passing.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally comes your generating the response. Again, query, knowledge sources.
Krish NAik: Okay, and from here, my response prompt. So, in the response prompt, can you see the query, the knowledge, and the sources? Everything that I am passing it?
Krish NAik: in one shot, and based on that, your final LLM generation that will take place. So this is the final look.
Krish NAik: Now, I have not done any specific categorization, like, correct, incorrect, or ambiguous, right?
Krish NAik: Now, I am just calling this function debC process, and I'll be directly calling it. So, one by one, retrieve the document, evaluate the document, then this is the max score, so determine the action based on the evaluation scores that I'll be getting. So, I have added this print statement. So, once you get, you will be getting the eval scores of every document.
Krish NAik: Then if max 0.7. I'm not writing that, so here, I've written this condition. Max score greater than 0.7. It means what?
Krish NAik: I'm telling my chunk is correct.
Krish NAik: Then, if the max score is 0.3, it means that chunk is not correct in relevant information, so simply performing a web search. Now, else, print, so you can write the condition, or simply through an else, print ambiguous, combining the retrib context as well as the web search.
Krish NAik: Both the things. Once you have this, both the things that needs to be concatenated, and passed it to the LLM to get your final response.
Krish NAik: Alright, then printing out the final knowledge, the sources, okay, all those things.
Krish NAik: So, here, let me pass it.
Krish NAik: Now, based on the PDF, I think, what are the main causes of the climate change?
Krish NAik: Okay, if I try to run it.
Krish NAik: Sign, you can keep this condition according to you. Okay, in some implementations, I have seen this 0.8 also.
Krish NAik: They are 0.75 also.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the, this score is 0.25.
Krish NAik: There is no certain logic.
Krish NAik: on this one.
Krish NAik: It has to be decided by you.
Krish NAik: Alright, the first one is the processing the query, what are the main causes of the climate change?
Krish NAik: So, right now, yes, retrieve 3 documents, the evaluation scores for those 3 documents are pretty high. Right now, I can see that 0.9, 0.9, 0.6. Action, correct, using the retrieve document. Okay, and then, based on that, we'll be getting the response from the end.
Krish NAik: Now, let's look into the other example.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, how did Harry beat, Quarrel? So, I think this is Harry Potter context, okay. Alright, now here, one by one, here, retrieve 3 documents in all the cases, I got, the evaluation scores are 000,
Krish NAik: Okay, action incorrect, okay. And performing the web search, then comes error parsing search the results, because zero things, because based on the query that I… so final knowledge from here, whatever through that result that got, like Voldemort, I can see here, this is much more from Harry Potter perspective.
Krish NAik: And finally, the response that I have.
Krish NAik: So I can see Harry Potter defeated Quirrell in the Philosopher's Stone through a combination of bravery.
Krish NAik: protective magic of this, okay, and then the response that I can see. And right now, the actual web sources links also that I have added.
Krish NAik: Now, if I try to, create, so if I try to add, do this.
Krish NAik: Mmm…
Krish NAik: Okay, let's try to add some keyword climate.
Krish NAik: with Harry Potter, in that movie.
Krish NAik: If you don't, Do you want, that, link of the climate one?
Krish NAik: Let me know then. I think it is available in the internet, you can search also. If you don't have, just wait, I'm sharing if you need it.
Krish NAik: I think, somewhere, that link, I have bookmarked it.
Krish NAik: I'm sharing this. 22P, where is that… Understanding climate… I forgot.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, next time I will just understand don't remember to repeat it.
Krish NAik: Last time, I thought I kept it.
Krish NAik: We're dominating.
Krish NAik: And pass any PDF which is not necessary.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, I will just drop the file that I'm using it here.
Krish NAik: I think your computer, just within the chat, I'm dropping it.
Krish NAik: Where is the PDF that I am using?
Krish NAik: Understood. I've shared it in the chat. You can get it.
Krish NAik: Mohit is asking why we are providing the document here.
Krish NAik: Mohit?
Krish NAik: If I don't… Pass any document from where it will fetch the chunk.
Krish NAik: Did this search, what are the main causes? Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Usually, I have shared the PDF. From chat, later on, I will be adding it.
Krish NAik: Now, just provide something related to climate, okay?
Krish NAik: So, something, let's, Let's take… okay.
Krish NAik: Let's take this keyboard. I will pass something junk right now.
Krish NAik: Impact of climate, in the movie, Let's see.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see, directly, 00000, in that case.
Krish NAik: Okay. This is fine.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: In the environment, and tell me about the…
Krish NAik: In both the cases.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in this case, I feel that, based on the query, like, if I would have done a query decomposition here, through, and I can actually break it, and based on that, two levels of things that can be done.
Krish NAik: Evaluation metrics are the same one. The evaluation metric doesn't change. You can use faithfulness on other things.
Krish NAik: site. Those things already we have covered. You can use RAGAS, Deep Evel, or RICI, so many things are there.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is one implementation, I think, that we have done it.
Krish NAik: I have another implementation also of CRAC, but again, it's the same thing, I think.
Krish NAik: This one is with respect to lan chain.
Krish NAik: Yeah, it's pretty much the same thing.
Krish NAik: Alright, now we'll be jumping into self-grad.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mitesh, alright.
Krish NAik: Right now, in the chat, I have shared it.
Krish NAik: whoever is asking, Aniruda, I cannot see the doc in the chat. Right now, I think I have shared the PDF, but you guys can see it in the chat.
Krish NAik: Got the same PDM, I am using it for more than one month now.
Krish NAik: Yes, okay, great. Now, the next one, okay, so let me do a save.
Krish NAik: Okay, now we'll be talking about, a little bit the self-reflective ad.
Krish NAik: Yes, later on, I will add it in the Datadocs folder, and I will push it after the class.
Krish NAik: Now, with respect to yourself reflective rag.
Krish NAik: Right now, I've shared it in the chat, later on, I will put it in motion. Rather than putting it in motion, I will put it in there.
Krish NAik: And just wait, because I feel that I have this in my data folder, but
Krish NAik: Somewhere, everyone else's fab… I have this, but this data folder…
Krish NAik: It's in my git ignore, or what?
Krish NAik: Ctrl-A, data… Okay, one more time.
Krish NAik: Okay, it is… it was commented only. Then it was fine, no?
Krish NAik: I think I will later look into, I think, somewhere I have done a PDF, I think.
Krish NAik: PDF… star.edu.
Krish NAik: Okay, later on, I will update that in a separate folder.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, now let's start with our next discussion, which will be the cell brack.
Krish NAik: Self-frag and self-reflective ride.
Krish NAik: Actually, like, in the paper, it's called self-reflective rag only.
Krish NAik: But people call it Elsaran.
Krish NAik: Majorly in the market.
Krish NAik: Galaxy RAG, SRAG, Adaptive for ERAG in that way.
Krish NAik: You can use the term SRAG, self-reg, self-relative, same stuff.
Krish NAik: If you know the paper, nothing to worry about.
Krish NAik: Now, in this paper, what will happen? This is nothing with respect to your retrieval. This is with respect to your…
Krish NAik: generation much more. So this paper is around. So let's go through the paper once.
Krish NAik: So, you can see self-rag learning to retrieve, generate, and critic through self-reflection. Okay, so self-reflection means, generally, like, self-realization toward the rag.
Krish NAik: So, despite their remarkable capabilities, LLMs often produce responses containing factual inaccuracies.
Krish NAik: Due to their soul reliance on parametric knowledge, they encapsulate.
Krish NAik: RAG, ad hoc approach that augment LLM's language models with retrieval of relevant knowledge decreases search issues.
Krish NAik: Alright, augmenting based on the language models, and RAG for sure, they will be decreasing such issues because RAG breaks non-parametric, things into the picture.
Krish NAik: However, indiscriminately retrieving and incorporating a fixed number of retrieved passages, regardless of whether the retrieval is necessary.
Krish NAik: Or passages are relevant.
Krish NAik: diminishes the LM versus the language model versatility.
Krish NAik: No.
Krish NAik: See, really, if you think about right now, they are talking about incorporating a fixed number of retripped passages. So, these are referred to as chunks. They're not using the term chunks, but that retrieval of passages. Regardless whether the retrieval is necessary or passages are relevant.
Krish NAik: diminishes the LLM, or that language model versatility, and can lead to unhelpful response generation. So here, the main focus is with respect to
Krish NAik: the language model response generation. So, they are talking about, we propose or we introduce a new framework called as self-reflective RAG that enhances language model's quality and factuality through retrieval and self-reflection.
Krish NAik: What it is improving? Enhancing, and language models quality.
Krish NAik: It means that the quality of the LLM, in simple terms, it means that the output quality.
Krish NAik: Through retrieval and self-reflection, our framework trains a single arbitrary language model that adaptively retrieves messages on demand
Krish NAik: Okay, now, Adaptly retrievers the passages on demand.
Krish NAik: So, generally, this on-demand, generally, it comes with the query only, and generates the reflects on reactive processes and its own generation using special tokens called as reflection tokens that they are referring.
Krish NAik: Generating the reflection tokens make the language models controllable through inference phase, enabling it to tailor its behavior to diverse task requirements.
Krish NAik: So right now, these, reflection tokens that they are talking about in our implementation, we'll be talking about them.
Krish NAik: To, this, particular experiment showed that self-tracked 7 billion model tests and 13 billion model tests significantly outperformed state-of-the-art LLMs.
Krish NAik: and RAG models on a diverse set of tasks. Specifically, the self-rag outperforms ChatGPT for sure, like ChatGPT, how ChatGPT will know your custom, your own database.
Krish NAik: And rag on, augmented Llama 2 chat on Open Domain Q&A, alright? On top of a very specific dataset, question answering.
Krish NAik: They have checked it, and it should. But really, like, the experiment is not… Pometic detail. CRAC implementation.
Krish NAik: is much more dominant in the market as compared to the self-rac. Selbrac is used
Krish NAik: bit lesser. So that's why self-drag is an older paper as compared to CRAG. CRAG paper is much more newer implementation. Because here, the focus is much more on the quality
Krish NAik: of the language model. It means that how we can
Krish NAik: generate better responses for the LLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now let's look into… now, this is the main diagram that they have.
Krish NAik: Now, in this diagram, when you see, so this is a simple rag, and this is their rag that they are talking about. So, in this rag prompt, how did the US kids get their names? Retrieve the top K documents, okay, then, like, from the retriever, you will be getting the chunks. Prompt LLM with K docs.
Krish NAik: You have combined this, and then, based on that, you'll be getting the information.
Krish NAik: So, yes, the results from the LLM can be contradictory. Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, in their solution, they are talking about the self-reflective rad. So, here's the prompt, the same prompt that is coming here. So, whenever is the prompt, guys, so prompt means not the prompt, think the prompt as a query.
Krish NAik: Okay, don't think about the prompt that, we… so it's pretty much the query right now.
Krish NAik: Now, I hear retrieval on demand. Okay, step one.
Krish NAik: So, generally, in default, the retrieve K documents, but on demand state, it's saying that, okay, now, EV states got their names from a variety of sources, multiple types of sources that are mentioned. So, 1, 2, 3.
Krish NAik: So, now it will be searching on 3 different types, so prompt plus 1 source, prompt plus 2 source.
Krish NAik: To prompt first three sources.
Krish NAik: Okay, now here are the categories that they have been taken. So, generate segments in parallel. So, the prompt is basically the query right now.
Krish NAik: So don't get confused, like, prompt is, like a prompt template that I am passing. So, it's pretty much the query on top of document 1. Prompt, again, the query with respect to your document 2. Because this 1, 2, 3. This 1, 2, 3 is from where?
Krish NAik: This is actually from this one.
Krish NAik: The benefit will come, because actually here you check through each of the, chunks with the prompt, because
Krish NAik: Here, directly, we don't look into the queries.
Krish NAik: And here, also, we have kept a condition of relevant, irrelevant, two major conditions, whether if you feel that this particular information is relevant or not.
Krish NAik: And then, whenever it is irrelevant, we support that document. If it is irrelevant, we don't support the document, it means that's why marked with a red color mark.
Krish NAik: Okay? And then, finally, once I have the California name.
Krish NAik: Was this original 16th century, that particular information.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, see, when you look into this 11, out of 50 states.
Krish NAik: This document is supported, so from here, like, I can say this can be picked up, this can be picked up, and this is a partially correct document. Not entirely correct, but yes, partial information that I feel is
Krish NAik: Okay, so somehow that ambiguous thing, 50% correct, 50% not relevant.
Krish NAik: Now, step 3, okay, critique the outputs and select the best segment. Now, if I say which is the best segment, this is the best one. After that, this is the one, and finally, like, this is… which is totally irrelevant.
Krish NAik: So here, it's saying that, okay, the US states got their names from a variety of sources. After that, the next one is 11 of the 50, this one came.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the next part, which is 26 states are named. Again, finally, the third part, which is partial one, that information will also go out.
Krish NAik: Okay, and now, this step is just like a loop. It will keep on repeating. Initially, with 1, I can see all the green colors. Finally, like, in the third condition.
Krish NAik: Half green, half yellow, it means that 50% correct, 50% wrong. Red is totally… which is out of the context. We don't support those documents.
Krish NAik: Now, see what they have done in simple things. So here, they are talking about, if simply in the figure 1, overview of the cell prep. So, the cell plug learns to retrieve, critique, and generate text messages to analyze the overall generation quality, factuality, and the variability. It means that from a specific chunk.
Krish NAik: You actually look into that, whether in this chunk, what are the information that can… that is factually correct.
Krish NAik: And whenever I'm talking about factually correct, it means that, using self-trag, actually, the faithfulness increases. Using CRAG, the recall increases. So, from the eval.
Krish NAik: Prospect, I'm just telling, though they are not mentioned, but generally this happens whenever we do the implementation.
Krish NAik: We don't know.
Krish NAik: The LLM will do it, Mohit, at any point of time. How do we know it is relevant or relevant? Okay, that part, the LLM will do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, looks like ASRAG is Agent, acerAG is similar to Agent TKI. No, no, no, ASRAG. ARAG can be implemented in Agent TKI, because in Langraph, anywhere you can do the implementation.
Krish NAik: I've done the implementation in the same thing that can be done in LangRobots.
Krish NAik: There's nothing related to Agent TKI. You can think about, if you think that tool, external tool that I'm calling DuckDuckGo, if you think that, okay, that tool can be a separate agent than me. Otherwise, there is no agent still now. Alam.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, finally, prompt, write an essay for your best summer vacation. No retrieval, my summer vacation is when my family, and based on that. So, if you… in the case there is no retrieval, then again, the fallback will be based on web search, though they have not mentioned it here.
Krish NAik: Web search, so generally, the combination of CRAT and self-rack is widely used. Now, really, when I look into this, okay, again, let's go through the steps that they have mentioned.
Krish NAik: Prompt, basically the query, how did the US kids get their names? Step one, retrieve on demand.
Krish NAik: Okay, so retrieve on demand means what?
Krish NAik: Simply, when you say on-demand.
Krish NAik: It means that the retrieval will be coming from some vector database only, no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because here, 1, 2, 3, how these things will come.
Krish NAik: Into the picture.
Krish NAik: Because right now, on demand, at the end of the day, your context lies on vector team.
Krish NAik: Okay, but, why…
Krish NAik: Once you have your very specific chunks, then you can actually use them. So that's why you query with those chunks which has been attached.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, like, in the retrievals, this process is based entirely on cosine similarity. But think about if I take my query and the chart to a prod, and if I ask it to do some type of critic, when I'm talking about list, use some type of evaluation criteria.
Krish NAik: Rather than only focusing on the cosine similarity, why not use an LN?
Krish NAik: That's the simple idea here.
Krish NAik: Now, Raul is telling the system learns when to stop or continue. This is a continuous loop, it keeps on going, till the time this, condition when the system, realized that everything is correct.
Krish NAik: Because… but, again, in this particular condition, I feel that, again, information loss always happens, because it breaks the order, that's why.
Krish NAik: Same thing happens in CRAG, the same thing happens here also.
Krish NAik: But again, that is a very small con. You get a much more added benefit, where the idea is to focus on much more relevant content than irrelevant content.
Krish NAik: Now, Rahul is telling, what quality metrics. So, generally, whenever you are working with CRAG, it always helps you to increase your recall, and with respect to, this one, okay, so, the answer relevancy increases, okay, according to RAGAS, the implementation, if I see.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now in the implementation, we'll be looking into that.
Krish NAik: Now, a lot of other things that has been mentioned here, but, really, like, concurrent RAG work, policy, because sometimes people apply reinforcement learning also inside RAC using self-reflection.
Krish NAik: But right now, no reinforcement learning or reward-based system.
Krish NAik: has been applied. Now, let's look into the algorithm. So, they are telling generator LMR language model M, Retriever R, a large-scale passage collections, which are basically the chunks D1 to DN. In the input, what we are passing, input from X, so basically the query and preceding generation Y output the next segment one.
Krish NAik: M predicts retrieve given X comma Y, so this particular condition of the preceding generation that we have taken.
Krish NAik: Y less than T right here, so if retrieve is equal to yes, then retrieve the relevant
Krish NAik: text passages or retrieve the channels from your main vector DB. Once you have those information, then you can move ahead with the generation part.
Krish NAik: Once the generation is done, then the next step is basically to do the critic. So here, is relevant or not, that's why that condition is supported or not, is useful or not. So both the conditions that has been taken, and so this is the self-critic rule. So, this is where it performs a self-reflective or a self-re…
Krish NAik: realization whether I do have relevance.
Krish NAik: context, okay, for my final generation. If it is there, it's good. Otherwise, again, the loop continues.
Krish NAik: If else, if the retrieval is no, then M generates a predict XYT given the X. And generally, even you can add a web search here also, because if everything fails, then where it should go?
Krish NAik: So, in the recent versions of CellPrag, people, that's why, combined CRAG with CellPrag.
Krish NAik: Because, again, that condition, nobody talks about.
Krish NAik: Because if you have something which is totally out of the context, then from where it will face the uncertainty.
Krish NAik: Because in this paper, they have not discussed about it.
Krish NAik: The idea is that the LLM knows everything which is not in the real-time scenarios, it doesn't happen.
Krish NAik: So, people always use a combination of CRAG with your SRI.
Krish NAik: Now, some four types of reflection tokens that they are talking about, and let's talk what are these tokens. So, one token, so right now, these are simple categories. Like, one is the retrieve token, so X with X comma Y, so yes, no, continue, three different type of outputs, decide when to retrieve R.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the first one, because the, retrieve with R means the call to the retriever, that the retriever will be invoked or not. Then comes is relevant, so X comma d, D refers, again, to your chunks, relevant or irrelevant.
Krish NAik: Okay? So D provides useful information to solve X.
Krish NAik: Now, the next definition is supported, so fully supported, or partially supported, or three supported, again, 3 categories in the output. So, all of the verification worthy statement, NY is supported by D.
Krish NAik: According to the pseudo-logic that they have kept it. And finally, is useful, XY, so this is another output level, so where you are marking, 54321.
Krish NAik: So, Y is a useful response? 2X. 2X means X is basically the query right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so based on the query, yes, I can see that we are getting a useful response.
Krish NAik: Now, generally, like, again, this algorithm, little bit modification that we'll be doing.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, with respect to, again, inference overview, the training, there is no actual training, you have to understand, most of the things happen much more in inference level, just like CDAT.
Krish NAik: No separate training modules. So, training means introducing of weights and biases, so there are no certain things here.
Krish NAik: Now, okay, is the support, different from relevance? First relevance, then support comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: If something is relevant, then only it will be supported. If something is irrelevant, then no support that comes.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if there are 20 final chunks, then there will be 20 additional LLM calls since TS. LLM calls will be more for sure, because this entire thing will be judged by the LLM for this particular output conditions. It means everywhere LLM call data, I have to meet.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Nawa… Critic part, actually, the critic is done by the LLM, no?
Krish NAik: the LLM will look into your query, and based on the dense reader passages, whether it's helpful or not. Whether it's relevant, if it is relevant, then it will reach the condition of fully supported.
Krish NAik: That's why the first thing, if you look into if retrieval is equal to yes, then retrieve the rest, relevant text passages. The first condition is relevant.
Krish NAik: Then only it comes to the is supported. First, you need to check the relevancy, then only the support comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: If it is supported, then the condition is useful.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that,
Krish NAik: Thus, this is the main critic part that you have.
Krish NAik: So, first, the relevancy condition needs to be satisfied, then only the supported condition can be done.
Krish NAik: Alright, now the final ranking, if you really look into the rank.
Krish NAik: So first of all, the first condition is the relevancy, the first condition, then the supported condition, and then you have the use condition, which is the useful condition.
Krish NAik: Useful means the final answer, you are ready to actually get it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this particular implementation, again, let's look into that.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is another, training examples which has been provided.
Krish NAik: Now, in our case, so, input, try an essay for the base summer vacation, okay, and input, like, how did the… in both the cases, two different things that has been provided. Now, output, okay, you have this output, my best summer vacation was a magical escape.
Krish NAik: Now, Azure Water, Charming, whatever the things that has been mentioned. Now, the augmented output.
Krish NAik: Here, if you are directly looking to.
Krish NAik: The normal conditions here, no retrieval. My summer vacation was a magical escape to the coastal town of Santorini.
Krish NAik: Alright, because… Really, with respect to this augmented part. So, what is the meaning of augmented?
Krish NAik: some changed form, always remember that. It means that
Krish NAik: some type of metaphorosis which has been done. So sometimes, the core context will remain the same, but somehow the form can be changed. But when I look here, with respect to the output, the augmented output, no retrieval is required.
Krish NAik: Why? Because I feel that it's pretty much the same stuff which has been mentioned here. So that's why the green color is here. It means that pretty much supported version. Now here, on top of the original output, if I look into the augmented output, the critical M version.
Krish NAik: How did the US states? First of all, in the output, I'm getting 1 out of 50 states come from persons, for instance, Louisiana was named in the honor of King Louis, and Georgia was named King George, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Now, with respect to the critic, when I look into, alright, here, in this case, no retrieval was required, but in this case, yes, we are looking into the retrieve part.
Krish NAik: So, that's why that on-demand… so, based on this, based on the augmented output, if I look into the retrieve, the first part that we have.
Krish NAik: some sentence based on some passage, 1, 2, 3, these are actually the reference from your main course, I can say, chunk from vector D.
Krish NAik: Then comes, okay, the first one, relevant, the second document that is coming, 11 out of 50 states.
Krish NAik: Now, if you really look into, yes, comes from the person, here also comes from the person. So, somehow, 50-50, because 11 out of 50, here it is mentioned. But here, 1 out of 50. So, that's why, factually, partially correct. So, that's why it's supported.
Krish NAik: I can say, but again, that information of 11 out of 50, and here, like, 1 out of 50.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see the differences, because, like, one that came, alright, both the conditions are taken into account. Now, for this particular statement, for instance, Louisiana, named in the honor, this is also relevant, I can say.
Krish NAik: Now, for instance, Luciano named after this king and George.
Krish NAik: Now, if you really look into this part, partially correct through what they have told, but if you really look into this output.
Krish NAik: I feel that this is also pretty much relevant, and that can be supported, because this main relevancy from the chunks.
Krish NAik: Because in my main chunk, I know that somewhere this information of 11 by 50 was there. Look into our previous one.
Krish NAik: Can you see here? In one, I was getting that 11x50,
Krish NAik: Always remember, because, see, in the next figure, they are not showing that. But actually, you have to understand that, okay, from somewhere, they are getting that information.
Krish NAik: Okay, so they are not exactly showing, but you have to assume from your previous picture that has been taken into account.
Krish NAik: Now, for this statement, for Louisiana was named after King Louis. Alright, again, I feel that this is partially correct only.
Krish NAik: So, useful, yes, it is useful.
Krish NAik: Now, these are some training examples which have been provided. The left example does not require retrieval, while the right one requires retrieval. Those passages are inserted. So, passages are what? Champs.
Krish NAik: More examples are provided in Appendix Table 4 later on that we can look into.
Krish NAik: Alright, so pretty much a different generator module that can be used, but really, with respect to the implementations.
Krish NAik: Separate models are not required. Pretty much direct implementation using an LLM that we can do it. Okay? Now, let's go through this particular part of the mean people, okay? This is the… 3.3 is the most important part.
Krish NAik: So, right now, they are talking about generating self-reflection tokens to self-evaluate its own output.
Krish NAik: It means that the output of the language model needs to be self-evaluated. This makes the self-lab controllable during the inference phase.
Krish NAik: Now, just think about, if you feel that your generated output is wrong, what is the first thing that you will be working on? Tell me, according to that.
Krish NAik: What is the first thing we'll be looking into?
Krish NAik: The retrieved one.
Krish NAik: junk… Could you please elaborate Kate told?
Krish NAik: The red trip document means chunks only, no.
Krish NAik: Now, if you have the LLM generated one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then, okay, if you feel that the answer is not good.
Krish NAik: Then, see, the main thing is that you will be going back to the retriever only.
Krish NAik: Because in any implementations, the main thing is the retrible. You need to optimize, somehow, your iterable process much more better, rather than only
Krish NAik: Focusing on your generation part.
Krish NAik: Now, if you try to check your current LLM response with your query.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that, if you try to fetch the chance.
Krish NAik: Now, really, you have the query, so for sure you can fetch out the junk, there is no dependency. But when you try to compare them, query, chance, and your output.
Krish NAik: So, in certain level, I can see that…
Krish NAik: Yes, at every point of time, it is not required.
Krish NAik: Because if you think from the metrics perspective in Raga's, I taught you, like, answer relevancy. Based on the query, if you feel that your answer is correctly responded.
Krish NAik: Then, do you think that you will move to the next steps?
Krish NAik: Let me know.
Krish NAik: Because again, shh.
Krish NAik: this… because I give much more dominance to CRAG as compared to Silver.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: If you feel that your answer relevance is pretty much high, then will you do this particular type of implementation? Even web search is not here leave that part. That is another con. That's why the combination of CRAG and SRAG is used.
Krish NAik: Because, yes, it helps, I can say, but again, the fundamental thing we need to work on
Krish NAik: Which is your retriever at the end of the day?
Krish NAik: Left 1 doesn't. So, I give less dominance to this paper as compared to CRAT. CRAD paper is having much more dominance.
Krish NAik: Okay, in major implementations also. Self-rag, it's fine. On the top of a module, you can add it, but again, not in every use case. In every use case, I can use CLAT, but self-rag inference, I don't prefer it, using it always.
Krish NAik: It's just, like, an optional module that I prefer.
Krish NAik: Totally, I can play based on the metrics and others.
Krish NAik: Because, LLM generation quality is directly handled by your
Krish NAik: retriever. If your retrieval quality is bad.
Krish NAik: Then again, self-rack can do nothing. You have to understand.
Krish NAik: Because the dependency in their algorithm, what they have mentioned.
Krish NAik: Okay? Yes. If the retrieval part is yes, and majorly, most of the time, this will happen, the retrieve part, and then that particular generation.
Krish NAik: Anyway, so that's why we are, talking about this particular… I feel that,
Krish NAik: This is a module, again.
Krish NAik: better modules are there, because with this, what is the con? Again, like, every time the LLM call will be brought into the picture?
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I feel that less importance
Krish NAik: as compared to CRAG. I feel CRAG is a must module in every rag-based system, whereas CELPRAG optional module. I can use a combination of CRAG with CELPRAG, that's why I give lesser dominance to CellPrac. In major implementations, you will see that. People will bring it, but it's always about the CRAG.
Krish NAik: Like, all the main focus is always towards your retrieval quantity.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… A few implementations, building their own training sets and other things that has been done.
Krish NAik: But, really, like, we won't be building our main sets. Okay, and, the combination of CRAG and SRAG really works out.
Krish NAik: Using only cell cracker is bad. See, remember.
Krish NAik: there are 3 conditions that comes. Use only CRAG, use only cell crack, or use only Cell plus serum.
Krish NAik: Never use only self-rad.
Krish NAik: Always use CRAT and the combination of CRAT plus self-rad.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm repeating.
Krish NAik: Only self-rag doesn't help sleep.
Krish NAik: Yes, Methisht, that combination is in Project 3.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now let's get back and let's quickly look into the notebook.
Krish NAik: That's why I discussed these two conditions, because in your project three, you have these two parts.
Krish NAik: That is exactly the same thing that we have discussed so many times, Dinesh.
Krish NAik: CRAG is for retrieval, and self-reg is for generation.
Krish NAik: Always remember.
Krish NAik: Okay? Okay, the screen sharing stopped, it looks like.
Krish NAik: desktop tool.
Krish NAik: No, write to him in the US if you want to leave, because this is a small notebook only.
Krish NAik: Not a very complex one.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: as multiple steps are there, that retrieval decision on demand, that we need to work on. Then comes your document retrieval, it's pretty much the same step. Then comes that relevance evaluation, access whether the retriever documents to the query.
Krish NAik: Then comes the response generation. Okay, now the response generation needs to be evaluated based on the chunks, and then supporting the assessment that is support that particular condition.
Krish NAik: And that utility valuation, right? It's the usefulness of every generated response.
Krish NAik: So, that's where all the methods, one by one, multiple classes that will be creating it, okay? So, let's do it.
Krish NAik: Alright, pretty much it worked. Let me just parse the PDF.
Krish NAik: Let me create the vector store.
Krish NAik: I changed the path, it looks like.
Krish NAik: the bolts.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, multiple chains that I'll be creating, so I'm just defining the prompt templates.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, a few benefits if you really think about.
Krish NAik: In simple terms, so according to your own assessment. Which one you feel that which is more important, self-rac or CRA?
Krish NAik: Because I feel that the corpora which is used by self-rag is pretty much static as compared to CRAG. CRAG can actually fall back to your external retriever sources, that is one of the best things that I feel.
Krish NAik: Okay? And, really, like, here, the initial action is only two types of action that you have. One is the retrieval or not retrieval. Whereas here, the action types are much more better, where I feel can sit at the correct, incorrect, and ambiguous types.
Krish NAik: So that's why, in some cases, I feel always that's a better version of CRAG. So, like, because according to the CRAG paper, in the benchmark, it has been shown that CRAG with self-rag in one of the datasets, it really worked.
Krish NAik: So, the safer side, everybody picks, and in the other dataset, only CRAG work, not CRAG with SRI.
Krish NAik: So, that is the part which you need to do the experiment. When I work, I only do two experiments. CRAG plus SRAC combination, or only CRAG combination.
Krish NAik: Okay, because according to datasets, you will be getting different responses.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: No,
Krish NAik: Let's start with the first part. The retrieval response, this is determining if the retrieval is necessary or not. Now, this is a trigger, because in, cell crack, you need to take the decision on demand.
Krish NAik: That on-demand implementation that we have done this. So, given the query, determine if the retrieval is necessary.
Krish NAik: output only, yes or no. Only two conditions that we can do, like, yes, we can activate it, if and else conditions are there, according to the pseudocode that we have.
Krish NAik: Then comes relevance response, determines if the context is relevant.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in the description of this one, we kept it only relevant or irrelevant.
Krish NAik: output type.
Krish NAik: Okay, so simple decisions that needs to be taken. In the input variable, what I'll be passing, the major query and the context from the chunks. So, template given the query and the context determine if the context is relevant or not.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Then, in the next step, class, which comes a generation response.
Krish NAik: Now, here, generated response, or basically the LLM, the language model generated response, given the query and the context generated response.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the same pipeline which is used in the common drag also, standard drag.
Krish NAik: Then comes supporting the response. It means once you have the final response, you need to do the support also. Now, to do the support, what things that are required. So, determines if the response is supported.
Krish NAik: Description output fully supported, partially supported, no supported.
Krish NAik: These are the types.
Krish NAik: Now, input variable, I'm passing the response and the context. Context means, again, that chunk absorption.
Krish NAik: Now, template, given the response, and the context determine if the response is supported by the context, output fully supported, or partial.
Krish NAik: And then, finally, the utility response that I have. Okay, so here's the final rating that I'll be doing. In the final case, also, I think in the paper, it was mentioned.
Krish NAik: Here, I think 54321.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, 54321 already.
Krish NAik: So in the utility rating, the final… given the query and the response, rate the utility of a response from 1 to 5.
Krish NAik: Okay, now simply for everyone, I'm just creating the chains one by one. Okay, so the retrieval chain, the relevance chain, the generation chain, the support chain, and the utility chain.
Krish NAik: Because once I have them, directly, I can pass all these classes in the LLM structure output. And based on that, I'll be getting… So, all these things are available, so one by one, let's start. So, first of all, the cells,
Krish NAik: RAG logic flow. So, first of all, let's define the function. We'll be passing that query, access to vector store, and right now, topK is equal to 3.
Krish NAik: That we have selected. First of all, we need to determine if the retrieval is necessary. So, step one, determining if the retrieval is necessary. So, for that, you need the input data, I'm passing the query, I'm invoking the retrieval chain.
Krish NAik: Okay, so retrieval chain.info, inputData.response.strip.lower, print, retrieval decision, whether you want to go ahead with the retrieval or not.
Krish NAik: If the retrieval decision is yes.
Krish NAik: Then, step 2, retrieval relevant documents. This is where you are applying cosine similarity on top of your vector databases. Based on the query, it will return the top K, which is 3 for now. You are fetching out the context.
Krish NAik: Length of the context.
Krish NAik: Now, step 3, evaluate relevance of the retriever documents.
Krish NAik: Now, again, like, once you have retrieved the documents, again, you are trying to look for the relevancy of those documents.
Krish NAik: Now, in the next step, finally, you will be getting the total number of, documents, so here the relevance change that I will invoke, which will mark that, okay, now this particular chunk is relevant or not.
Krish NAik: So, for every chunk, that scoring mechanism, that will happen.
Krish NAik: And then finally, you'll be having the total number of relevant chunks.
Krish NAik: If there are no relevant chunks found, generate without the retrieval.
Krish NAik: Because then there is no purpose only, no? If there is no relevant chunks, so simply, like, no relevant text or chunks found. So, generating without the retrieval process.
Krish NAik: the input data query, context nor relevant context form. What will happen to this particular condition? Tell me, really.
Krish NAik: If you have no relevant context, then how?
Krish NAik: This particular fallback condition will work.
Krish NAik: Because this is one of the…
Krish NAik: measure this. If it gets, it's fine. I'm not worried about.
Krish NAik: But if there are no relevance context.
Krish NAik: then do you think that I should invoke the generation chain, yes or no? Just think.
Krish NAik: Here, we can use the search exactly correct.
Krish NAik: Exactly correct. So that's why in our implementation will be… because I feel that this part is actually the biggest con that I see. This needs to be modified somehow.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, then, if not condition, after that, we are coming out of the if, okay, and then finally, okay, print, generating a response using relevant context.
Krish NAik: This is fine, because once we have the relevant context, there is no issue, but what about if I don't have? Because we are appending that information in this particular list.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, for I, multiple responses. So, for i in context, enum, relevant context, generating the response. For the context, for every context, you are generating the responses, and you are appending in this response list.
Krish NAik: So, generation invoke chain, and from here, you'll be getting the response fine.
Krish NAik: Now, access the support. Now, once you have the responses with you, then you need to do that support.
Krish NAik: So, step 5, accessing support for responses. So, first of all, input data will be looking into the response and the context. Okay, and then we will invoke the support chain. In the support chain, again, we'll be passing our input data, okay, and from there, from this particular chain, whatever the response data I'll be getting.
Krish NAik: So, from here, I'll be getting a support assessment, and finally comes your, evaluate utility.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, so many changes one by one. This is a little bit longer as compared to C1, but finally, this is the evaluation where you do the evaluation of the responses one by one.
Krish NAik: So, in the input data, I'll be having the query condition, response, so query and responses.
Krish NAik: int, here, so… because I need the final answers in the int form, so I will be invoking the chain input data and the final response, because the scoring mechanism is there. 54321, so that's why that int.
Krish NAik: Then print utility.score, the final score that I'll be getting, all the responses that I'll be adding, okay, now this response, this is the support, this is the utility.
Krish NAik: So you'll be having all those things in a single list.
Krish NAik: Now, select the best response based on support and utility. As you have multiple responses based on multiple chunks, okay, because at every point of time, you are passing different context. So, for sure, there will be multiple responses.
Krish NAik: Now, once you have this, so, else condition, then the entire thing comes out.
Krish NAik: print generating without the retrieval part. And really, I don't, like, generating without the retrieval.
Krish NAik: then just think about this particular logic also. If you want to do any, generation without the retrieval.
Krish NAik: Then, what flu is this one? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: If you are doing any generation without the retrieval.
Krish NAik: Because the same thing was there, if you really think about it. If not relevant context, generation share is invoked. And this is… because these are fallback conditions that they have set, but again, this is, again, this can be the web search part.
Krish NAik: in the loop breaker condition, I know, but certain things that need to be updated.
Krish NAik: You.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, based on that, okay, so let me just pass a simple query.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, doing the assessment, a lot of things that will go.
Krish NAik: I think, okay, so first one, what was the impact? First of all, determining if the retrieval is necessary. By default, retrieval has to be necessary. If you think about directly based on query, can you do…
Krish NAik: That, generation tell me, because
Krish NAik: Based on this else condition, if you really look into the… this… The decision is, yes.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, just think about directly query, and if there is no context. So this needs to be a fallback for web search, that's why. So this is actually a very, very big no.
Krish NAik: Now, okay, the impact… First, okay, I'm initializing my retriever.
Krish NAik: Once the retriever from there, I'll be getting the top 3 documents, fine. Now, once I have those top 3 documents, let's do the relevancy of each chunk or each document.
Krish NAik: Now, document 1 relevance, so I have told, okay, so based on, the scoring mechanisms, we are getting relevant, relevant, relevant. So, the total number of relevant documents is 3.
Krish NAik: Once we have those three documents, then comes step four, which is generating the response using the relevant context. Standard, direct.
Krish NAik: Generating the response for context 1,
Krish NAik: Okay, so accessing support for Response One Retu app.
Krish NAik: Then, you have the support assessment, which is fully supported.
Krish NAik: Then step 6, again, for your, next one, so evaluating the utility. So, this is where that scoring mechanism of 54321 will happen. So here, the utility score is coming 5. Now, generating the response for context 2.
Krish NAik: Okay, now the next, because 3 relevant context that I have. So, this actual document becomes the context. Don't get confused that document is separate, and context is separate. So, based on my 3 chunks, so really, like, if you have 20 chunks, you can understand. If you have 50 chunks, this process will be pretty much a continuous one.
Krish NAik: So, the utility score, this is also 5, this is also 5, this is also 5.
Krish NAik: Alright, pretty much 555 that I am. Selecting the best response, the best response supported, fully supported, utilities equal to 5, the final response that comes.
Krish NAik: I can't really, like, with respect to the response, when I look, areas are particularly
Krish NAik: Really, the quality that I have.
Krish NAik: The Fertile response one, somehow towards the lower side, not really so much good. I can improve that better with CNAC debt, I feel.
Krish NAik: Because initially, when you're starting with a small A,
Krish NAik: A small minor change. Now, yield the same one here. So here, what will happen?
Krish NAik: Determining if retrieval is necessary.
Krish NAik: Retrable decision is directly no, generate without the retrieval. Final response?
Krish NAik: Harry Potter defeated Professor in the first book.
Krish NAik: Through a combination and whatever the response that is coming here.
Krish NAik: Now, tell me from where it's getting the final response.
Krish NAik: Because you have to first determine that whether retrieval is necessary or not.
Krish NAik: By default, in most of the rack system, it means that a direct fallback, it means that later on this web search can be done.
Krish NAik: In websites, retrieval happens, okay?
Krish NAik: Nada.
Krish NAik: White is no.
Krish NAik: Because…
Krish NAik: the context that you were asking, it is out of the rack context, so directly a fallback that comes here.
Krish NAik: Because the relevancy is very, very low in simple terms.
Krish NAik: So, the first step only to determining. That's by the concept of on-demand. So, the idea was, in self-right, every time invoking your retriever is not a priority.
Krish NAik: How about taking that particular decision by providing multiple examples?
Krish NAik: That was the main purpose.
Krish NAik: Okay, because here I've, retained that, but, if you really determine whether the retrieval is necessary or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, and everywhere, like, I'm making a chat open, chat call. So, simply, I know that based on the context, really, I can see that, yes.
Krish NAik: So, the final response is based on the scores from the three retrievals. That is for the first condition, not for the third one. The third one, the response comes from the LLM.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: This is the fallback condition.
Krish NAik: In the code, somebody is telling Mohit in web search retrieval app, where is web search? I'm not telling implementation of web search. This is this condition.
Krish NAik: So this is coming from the LLM. Is this part clear?
Krish NAik: Now, in this paper, it doesn't matter if the LLM knows it or not. They are valued LLM knows everything.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Later on, you can add one more group. If the LLM doesn't… knows about that, then later on, do a web search, tool call, API call, anything that can be added.
Krish NAik: Okay, but their assumption is LLM knows everything. That's why.
Krish NAik: Alright, majorly… I have added, if I look into our DDGS,
Krish NAik: Because in my major one, where have I added DTGS? People are telling web search, web search.
Krish NAik: Where in the port I have invoked that one. Let me just see.
Krish NAik: Because in my chain utility prompt here.
Krish NAik: Mmm… I've not defined anywhere DDGS.
Krish NAik: Whoever is telling me that, Amar and others, Because Matthews is correct.
Krish NAik: Amar, you were telling that, this is doing web search already when I test it.
Krish NAik: where have I implemented the web search? Because I'm looking into the code, I'm asking simply.
Krish NAik: I'm… wherever I use DDG, yes, that's why.
Krish NAik: Yes, I'm also reverse. The decision, for that particular decision, generally, in the paper, they are trained using their own custom set.
Krish NAik: Because this particular decision, you need examples. So, to provide those examples, you need to do that particular training.
Krish NAik: Okay, so am I… because, guys, just check, because I don't feel I'm using the web search here. Please let me know, because then, according… we will be going against the research paper only.
Krish NAik: import statement is there. See, what I did, previously the input was not working. I copied from the CRAG input cell, and I pasted it here.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because, just because to make the notebook work. Because the inputs were deprecated.
Krish NAik: Mmm…
Krish NAik: Now, Amar is asking, okay, Amar, you are passing a query
Krish NAik: What is the query? SharePay.
Krish NAik: share me that query.
Krish NAik: how to create an invoice in Ariba Network, alright?
Krish NAik: Let me copy that, and let me paste it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm going with this one.
Krish NAik: Nope.
Krish NAik: Death…
Krish NAik: That was right. Because this particular decision, it went directly.
Krish NAik: That's why, in the original paper, they have actually done it in. So, determine if the retrieval is necessary. Retrieval decision is yes. Step 2, retrieval, relevant documents. Retrieve 3 documents, all the documents are relevant. Then again, that fallback condition, no relevant context found. Final response. Now, create this one.
Krish NAik: this information from where it is getting. It is getting from LLM.
Krish NAik: I hope.
Krish NAik: You get that. There is no web search here.
Krish NAik: People were telling that.
Krish NAik: Now, what is the added benefit C? Generally, if this… just think about if the retrieval decision was known, then also this will be generated, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: See?
Krish NAik: If… How many of you are getting it?
Krish NAik: If this particular logic of retrieval decision was no, then what will be the answer?
Krish NAik: Then also the same answer only you will be getting no.
Krish NAik: So that's why, like, if that particular condition, generally for that particular condition, say in this paper, you need to do… that's why that example training that they have, brought it. So, data collection, generator learning, multiple other things that has been brought. Even if you look into RHL… RLHL. What is RLHF?
Krish NAik: DPU'd…
Krish NAik: You guys have worked with… because these are much more training-related. If you have not worked with, LLMs.
Krish NAik: RHF is not directly, but it's human feedback loop, yes, that's one.
Krish NAik: Is correct. Similarly, PPO. These are all trading ones. So, that's why the idea is to take, but again, I feel that to take the first decision.
Krish NAik: you need some type of training examples. Without the training examples, I don't feel actually this is a correct one, because it's simply clearing that, okay, if you pass that particular test of taking the decision.
Krish NAik: do we do the normal retrieval process, or the non-retrable? If this is a non-retrable directly, I can say do a web search and then see that directly, the optimized version.
Krish NAik: But here, to understand that, whether it should go, that decision-making capability can be increased by training examples. If you don't create training examples, it becomes much more harder.
Krish NAik: So, that's why, directly, they have taken that, okay? And you can see, right, based on the multiple type of task.
Krish NAik: Where they have taken this data collection for your generator.
Krish NAik: So they are actually training the generator model, and through that. Now, this implementation, yes, the added benefit is, if it falls back, no problem, the output will be pretty much the same. So that's why that particular conditioner looked at you.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think, till today, we will keep till this point only.
Krish NAik: Okay,
Krish NAik: If you want to check the other versions, I will push the other version also. I do have other implementations of the same one.
Krish NAik: Okay, or in the next class, before starting the project, we can do the discussion.
Krish NAik: It's in Notion, please check Notion Cinemas. Yesterday, I shared in that batch also
Krish NAik: KF Padarit Krishna, why you are asking for an email again?
Krish NAik: Because, PPO-based training, I don't prefer, according to this, self-right. I prefer much more DPO. DPO is direct, preference optimization. And here, they have taken that PPO-based approach, which is, like, proximal policy optimization, which is not widely used.
Krish NAik: Starting from 2020, like… Adaptive rad, yes, that is next topic.
Krish NAik: Okay, class is finished, here, people who want to drop, they can drop.
Krish NAik: Because PPO is a very unstable training environment, that I feel, so I don't prefer working with PPO a lot. Whereas, stability, you get much more in TPO-based ones.
Krish NAik: ChatGPT was actually trained on PPO, that was the interesting thing.
Krish NAik: But, Llama 2 and others, Zafar, good models are actually trained on DPA. Both the things are used, but stability is much weaker there.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Adaptive rag will come, because a lot of things in this syllabus we are going through.
Krish NAik: Because I thought to show this implementations with Langra, but again,
Krish NAik: If I show language, then again, state management, that is the main problem.
Krish NAik: screens, okay? Alright, you want to share, Saurabh?
Krish NAik: Let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Yes, Abhishek, in the self-right, rather than you were relying for sure on people.
Krish NAik: Okay, Saurabh, I will add you to panelists, others also, whoever is.
Krish NAik: Because, the oldest RH, like, human feedback loop technique was the PPO-based approach.
Krish NAik: Because in cell prep, that is the main decision. If it falls back, it's fine. That's why, generally, a combination
Krish NAik: In our project also, we'll be taking a combination of both.
Krish NAik: Yes, Warup, please proceed ahead.
saurabh verma: So, sir, I'm, sharing my screen.
saurabh verma: what I'm trying to do is, let me also share that.
saurabh verma: So, I have to upload a PDF, okay? And, then there'll be semantic search queries on that particular PDF.
saurabh verma: So, so here, I'll share you the PDF also.
saurabh verma: So, this is the PDF.
saurabh verma: Let's go.
saurabh verma: Okay, so these are… let me minimize this.
saurabh verma: So, these are the columns.
saurabh verma: Okay? And these are the queries.
saurabh verma: Okay, which query has been asked?
saurabh verma: And, later the user may enter a query which might be similar to this, so we have to identify
saurabh verma: what response was given. So, this is the problem statement.
saurabh verma: Now, this is one type of PDF, where 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 columns are there. Similarly, there is another, format, because many times it changes. So the baseline format is…
saurabh verma: this?
saurabh verma: Where, if you see, there is a serial number.
saurabh verma: Okay? There's category, again, those sections are there, okay? So, might be one column is more, or less, okay? So, this match.
Krish NAik: Fine, that is funny.
saurabh verma: Now, the challenge is that this particular PDF, if you see, the text can be read easily.
saurabh verma: But the other PDF, Is basically an image.
saurabh verma: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright.
saurabh verma: Now, what…
saurabh verma: I am… I'll just come to the point. Earlier, I used PyMuMit PDF, so it didn't work out.
saurabh verma: then I use PDF Plumber and OCR Tesseract, okay? So, these are the things I'm using right now to, because it will first identify, is there an image or not. If there is an image, then it will… there's a pipeline that is there, okay?
Krish NAik: Alright.
saurabh verma: So, the, but it is not able to read properly. Still, junk characters are coming up.
saurabh verma: Whereas, when I, wrote a prompt in CloudA, and I gave the same thing, it was able to do it correctly with the PDF plumber and give the CSV output.
saurabh verma: So… I'm trying to… I was trying to do this with the GitHub co-pilot and everything, But,
saurabh verma: It's trying, but I'm still not able to get…
saurabh verma: So, just wanted to know any high-level view, or maybe we can connect later.
saurabh verma: As per your availability.
Krish NAik: unstructured bios ni ki hai.
Krish NAik: Nice.
saurabh verma: Name a dock link next to use karatha. Ho PDF plumber bhi padata ushmein.
Krish NAik: First of all, I say, whenever you have these type of documents, the first thing is layout detection.
Krish NAik: Okay, ballot layout detect karte. Generally, for these type of device, like, if this is not the case, in your first one, table farmers in Docklinks, in Docklinks, it is available. Docklings will give you for sure better response.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, docklink, if you add docklink SAT, like, in multimodal, when I will teach you, granite docklink. So, in the backend, VLL, Claudic assay derive, because Claude has that multimodal support.
Krish NAik: Because of that, it is able to give you the correct response. First, layout detection happens whenever you are working with these type of documents. Fear in the next step we look into.
Krish NAik: So, start with docklings, then I can say that. Because EA Kyot, this will be a pipeline. First, you have to do this. If this condition satisfies, then this.
saurabh verma: Hmm, good.
Krish NAik: So, step by step. So, first of all, the layout detection, that, like, for layout detection, detect and two models are also there, which can be used.
Krish NAik: Like, unstructured also as… and don't use Tesser Act, use a better OCR background. Use ECOCR, Rapid OCR, KuchV, Paddle OCR, but don't use Tesseract. Tesser Act is very, very old stuff.
saurabh verma: Okay, okay. So, jo hamari wo class withi jismein, kafi sare wo PDFska docklink ka walajo session tha, that I revise again, right?
Krish NAik: But in those sessions, I've given you less examples with respect to these type of tables. Like, they go, multimodal draga with a parallion inclusion.
saurabh verma: U anew wala.
Krish NAik: case rag ickbar hojay mira, uske baat, multimodal rack pada ke, then I will jump into, like, graph rack B here, uske baat, then Langrah. So, then I'll be talking about, generally.
saurabh verma: Like.
Krish NAik: docklinka grinite search kann.
saurabh verma: dockling, with, gray night.
Krish NAik: Greenlight is the models that come from Docklink, directly available in Agingface. To download curriculate, easily direct start cursor subtit.
saurabh verma: use karna.
Krish NAik: Coach Bhi, like, everyone, like, Rapid OCR, Paddle OCR, easy OCR.
saurabh verma: Yeah, precision.
saurabh verma: And then it will see you.
Krish NAik: So this OCR engine can easily be, changed. Take care. For these type of documents, Azure Document Intelligence was really good.
Krish NAik: AWS card, Azure Document, then you have AWS Textract, Wubiach hai, Google Vision API jo hai, Wubiacha.
saurabh verma: Okay.
Krish NAik: uparga sarachios open source.
saurabh verma: aka nu I'll be in touch with you.
saurabh verma: karte na.
Krish NAik: Speaker.
Krish NAik: to both deno mereanam meleke to eventatan. I think unka interview hau ya thih.
saurabh verma: Cheers. Okay. Thank you, thank you.
Krish NAik: Others, anyone, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Because in the next projects, because next class, we will start with the project. In that project, hybrid rack, re-ranking, SRAC, CRAC, everything in one shot. That we'll be covering, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, the next project, but, next project, I won't be using catching and other stuff. Okay, the core idea is to focus on the functionalities. Okay, so that's why catching, less focus on logging, I can use,
Krish NAik: Until now, I think in your projects, I have not used LogGuru.
Krish NAik: So I think LogGuru, StructLog, these two are really good. So, probably one implementation that we can go ahead.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have, in the meantime, please check out the report.
Krish NAik: I think, that repo is… I'm just sharing, this is a repo.
Krish NAik: everything is not, available, but, the main discussion that I'm sharing, githal.com.
Krish NAik: This is the report that I'll be discussing. If you have time, spend at least 10 to 15 minutes just going through. It's not necessary, you go through everything, but this is the high level. Other components I have not added. Slowly, slowly, I'll be adding. Okay, let me just check the services once.
Krish NAik: CRAG, document processor, LLM service, self-reflecting, vector store, web search, all right. Core components, I think that, re-ranking and a few other things, those components I will add it.
Krish NAik: But here, majorly all the components that will be doing it.
Krish NAik: Okay, Viraj is telling, datalab.2 Chandra, okay, yes. I haven't tried this, but, recently, recently, like, another thing I'm telling for, Saurabh, okay, look always into the Omni, OCR benchmark.
Krish NAik: From here, you will… because DeepSeek OCR, which… like, the DeepSeek OCR got launched through
Krish NAik: Tiger, that is also a good one, so…
Krish NAik: They have… because Open Data Lacker, Omni OCR is really good. This you can look into, and this is the Omni OCR benchmark from… you can actually, look into different type of benchmarks. And this week, I think the famous one that got is the GLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, GLM models, as I am using, GLM OCR. This is also a good one.
Krish NAik: Okay? So this OCR, this is state-of-the-art right now, I feel. Like, really, it supports text, images, the output modality, this also, that you can check.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, the responses were good when I show you, as compared to Padalusi are better than Deep Si.
Krish NAik: this information, like, I'm telling you. This is last week.
Krish NAik: Okay, then you have minor U and other things.
Krish NAik: Subcellitis model is from NanoNets. This is also a really good one, but I'm telling about this model.
Krish NAik: Because, this model came only one week back.
Krish NAik: Eaglm, I'm sharing the link with you in the chat.
Krish NAik: liquid.
Krish NAik: This is also open source version. Now, really, you can see, if you try to compare them with Gemini 3, which is right now…
Krish NAik: In the top, it's performing better than that.
Krish NAik: At least on OmniDoc benchmarks, okay? And OmniDoc is the main one that I prefer for document parsing.
Krish NAik: Then there is other also, but I think in your case, like, this is computationally very, very expensive. I don't know how many of you know about Minery. This also comes from the Open Data Lab also.
Krish NAik: Transform complex documents, PDFs into LLM-ready Markdown.
Krish NAik: This is computationally very, very expensive.
Krish NAik: But if you have good, you can test it out, minor you also.
Krish NAik: Induces.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this link also I'm sharing.
Krish NAik: Not right.
Krish NAik: It was, Viraj at datalab.2 at Chandrahan. I have also seen that in few blocks.
Krish NAik: But, really, like, I've tested Deepse OCR, that also really does a very good one, but, really, the number of downloads, when I look into, there's also a good one, because 3 lakh, a lot of downloads, I can see.
Krish NAik: But, OLM OCR version 3 with deep-seq OCR. Little bit old, but yes, I feel that this can also do the job.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, Saurav, again, I'm sharing the link for this.
Krish NAik: Once you start multimodal, then you have to really know the knowledge from where you will be getting all those informations.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no. Matthews, you don't…
Krish NAik: No project is recommended. All the fundamental things I have already taught, all those things I will connect in one spot.
Krish NAik: Matthew, in the next project.
Krish NAik: once we complete the next project, then I'm planning directly. Let's cover Haystack, because really, haystack, I don't… I want to do it quickly only, because that is another framework, again. After Haystack.
Krish NAik: Let's cover graph rag.
Krish NAik: Now, in GraphRack, the DB selection that I was looking into.
Krish NAik: Like, Major League, I think you guys have worked with?
Krish NAik: Neo 4G, I think.
Krish NAik: What type of graph DVs you have used?
Krish NAik: You can let me know.
Krish NAik: First is always layout detection, you have to understand. Please use NEO4J turn. Neo 4G is bad, actually. Like, it does the job, but there are better things than NEO4G, that's why.
Krish NAik: Don't worry, till now I'm not planned exactly, I've not created the content.
Krish NAik: I can use Neo4G is widely used, but in graphs, like, Oracle 26 AI, the video that I shared go through that, it supports everything. Everything. Graph database, anything that you can fit up. That is one of the best.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: I shared in YouTube, no, that is with respect to vector databases, I think, that, Krish video.
Krish NAik: Boomish, or I can do this.
Krish NAik: Mmm, this one.
Krish NAik: This is really good, actually, like…
Krish NAik: if you are taking a decision in your organization, like, once… as I started working with Oracle 26, the content came from this particular team.
Krish NAik: I've been exploring this for more than 2 months.
Krish NAik: That's why, like, I raised the PR to the repo and everything. So if you,
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is actually the GitHub repo. You can check there, this is the Oracle Developer Relations.
Krish NAik: they have added my PR. This is the PR, again, I only added it. So, like, graph, vector, everything that can be done. So, I'm just showing you a few added benefits here.
Krish NAik: But, this is a notebook if you want to go.
Krish NAik: I think which one? Retail Agent, 2 months last week.
Krish NAik: Because almost the D.
Krish NAik: Even I'm confused, somebody has changed the name, or what?
Krish NAik: Last week, let me move into the history once.
Krish NAik: Finding match request… Memory context engineering notebook.
Krish NAik: I think this is someone.
Krish NAik: Application… okay, yes, this was actually the notebook. I think, it has been updated.
Krish NAik: Okay, it is the context engineering which has been added here. Fine.
Krish NAik: the main author. So this is really an interesting one if you feel that he's a memory context engineering, because this is created by our team only.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everything… I have only added all the code and everything.
Krish NAik: So this is a really good one, you can test it out.
Krish NAik: But for that, you need to create a Oracle Cloud account, and from there, you need to launch an instance of Oracle 26 AI.
Krish NAik: And just be sure, in the IP section, you add your IP, otherwise local, authentication problems that happens.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, guys, next class, because I think next class, again, I'll be traveling, okay, fine, after Project 3, little bit other things also we'll be talking about. Because that metadata enrichment part, I want to focus on.
Krish NAik: Little bit.
Krish NAik: Okay, because, till now, yes, but for metadata and enrichment, what are the things that needs to be done?
Krish NAik: I don't know, because on this month, Gleaner got very, very famous. So, Gleaner is one of the options, and the other option is Lang Extract, if anybody has used lang extract from
Krish NAik: Google. Okay, don't confuse the name, it's not from Landshake Community, it's from Google. So, those two things that we'll be exploring. The idea is focusing much more on NER-based solutions. Name entities.
Krish NAik: Okay, and these two are, right now, market standards. Everybody's using it. So, we'll be talking about that.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I think then I can conclude the session for today. Let's meet next week and start with our Project 3.
saurabh verma: Sir, just one last thing. The one which you mentioned, the pipeline, like, layout detection should be done and all that. So, any, white paper or something which I can go through, to implement?
saurabh verma: Or any article you can share me.
Krish NAik: Directly for implementations, or.
saurabh verma: Like you mentioned, the first layout detection has to be done, then you do this, there are steps to do the… make this pipeline.
Krish NAik: Dockling has a technical report, but again, that is…
Krish NAik: I don't think it will be there.
Krish NAik: Let me just search for Brockling Grenade.
Krish NAik: If I help it.
Krish NAik: For document and understand it.
Krish NAik: Mmm… Because DockerLink has that, there are some,
Krish NAik: multimodal track systems, all right. I'm sharing one link, check that.
saurabh verma: Okay, thank you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once you get, you'll get that Get Started with Knights link, there you'll be getting the tutorial, video, workshop, every link that.
Krish NAik: All right, guys, so, bye everyone, just be sure you are attending the next week, it's important, as we'll be connecting all the dots that we have called through the advanced RAC repo.
Krish NAik: One by one.
Krish NAik: So, let's meet next week. Thanks for joining, bye-bye, guys.